听译： 呔    墙头草   Macchiato02  Quixote2010  时间轴：呔  后期：墙头草
开拍
Action
他对收据的事不依不饶的 非留下我检查一遍系统不可
He's demanding that I stay and go over his system
我没法推辞 根本走不掉 对 就这样说
And I cannot get out of it,yeah
现在我们回到了全剧的开头
We are going back to the beginning
也就是决定后来剧情走向的阶段
To a defining era of Breaking Bad
在全剧完结前 我们想确保讲述一个前后连贯的故事
Before the series ended,we wanted to make sure that we had our origin story
确保我们能看到一些没拍的前情细节
That we saw everything that had been lost
对不起 今晚我要晚点儿回了
Sorry,but I'm gonna be late tonight
是因为Bogdan那家伙 他烦透了
Bogdan. He's got a bug up his butt
我们实际已经拍完最后一集了
We've shot 2 episodes since 514
但是由于我们必须给Bryan和Jesse刮胡子换造型
But because we had to shave Bryan and alter Jesse
所以在运作上 这个第五季十四集的引子必须放在最后拍
We logistically just had to place this teaser at the very end of our filming
所以对啊 这就是我们的最后一天了
So..yeah,this is the last day
不仅仅是第五季第十四集的最后一天 更是全剧最后一天
Not only of 514,but this is the last day of series filming
谢谢你亲爱的 我爱你 -我也爱你
Thank you honey,I love you,love you too
卡
Cutting
这是我们告别的日子《绝命毒师》最后的摄制日
It's our farewell day,our last day of shooting Breaking Bad
天气不错 华氏73或74度的样子 真是棒极了
It's beautiful,it's like 73 or 74 degrees,just fantastic
数百人为这个剧投入了无尽的热爱和辛劳 以及他们的艺术天才
So many hundreds of people had put so much work and their love and effort and artistry
有时候 我觉得我就像是来凑热闹的
That I just feel someday it's like I'm along for the ride
我现在也会这么想
I feel like that way today a little bit
今天非常糟糕 糟透了
This day is just terrible,awful,it's horrible
在这一切开始之前 我完全没有想到
I've no idea,back to the beginning of all this
这个剧会走这么远
That the show would go as far as it's gone
谁能想到这部剧会坚定地走到今天 并拥有这么多粉丝
Who knew this would have such legs would go so far and have so many fans
绝不折中:《绝命毒师》最终季制作记录
2004年2月 Vince和我正在打电话
It was in Feb,2004,Vince and I were talking on the phone
偶然间 我提了一下我在纽约时报看到的一篇报道
For some reason,I brought up this article that I read in new york times
是关于一个在自己公寓里制冰毒的人的
About a guy who was cooking meth in an apartment building
不知怎的 这个话题让我们开始谈论 这个主意是多么棒
And then somehow that morphed into us talking about that's probably a pretty good idea
也许我们可以试试写个房车制毒 赚点外快的故事
Maybe we should go around in an RV cooking meth to make some extra money
我还没反应过来 一份《绝命毒师》剧本就出炉了
And then before I know it,suddenly there was a Breaking Bad script
事实上 我刚接手这部剧的创意时 关于要不要做下去
Actually the idea of doing the show when it came across my desk
我的想法是 听起来有点意思 但风险也是有的
Was,sounds interesting,a little bit risky
但是你知道 这就是我们 有冲劲儿
But you know,this is who we are,scrappy
我们追求的就是 有趣的独特的大想法
And we are gonna go for the big interesting,different idea
而这就是一个 有趣的独特的大想法
This is certainly big interesting and different
《绝命毒师》不再只是纸上谈兵的时机成熟了
The time had come where Breaking Bad was no longer going to be just a script and words on a page
我们想将它付诸现实
We wanted to make it a reality
我们找了网络合作伙伴AMC来帮助我们
We have found our network partner AMC to make that a reality
我们走了下流程 见了AMC的负责人
We've had a process here,where we were going to meet with the chairman of the studio
Michael Lynten希望他能支持我们
Michael Lynten,to have him give us his blessing
他们向我描述了剧情
They described the show to me
然后我就说我来理一下 这是个高中化学老师的故事
And I said so let me get this straight,this is about a high school chemistry teacher
中年有家室 得了癌症 然后他决定走上邪路 成为了一个毒枭
Middle-aged,children,he has cancer and he decides to go off and become a crystal meth dealer
然后他们说 对就是这样
And they say that's right
当时的会面如果是一部电影的话 会有紧张的咬指甲的瞬间
If it were movie there would have been be nail-scratch
当时一片寂静 Michael从剧本中抬起头
It was just silence,Michael looks up from the paper
他在听 却没和任何一个人作眼神交流
He is hearing everything but making no eye contact
然后他说道 这是我听过的 最疯狂最糟糕的电视剧创意
And says,that is the craziest and worst idea for a television show I've ever heard
我不管谁写的剧本 这简直疯了
And I don't really care who writes it,that's nuts
你必须明白 此时此刻我们已经投入了很多
You have to understand at this point we are so far in
而这个我们刚刚给Michael讲的故事
And the story that we've just told Michael
是我们抱着极大的信念来创作的
Had done with so much conviction
我们真的没有回头路可走
There's really no getting out if it
然后他们说 我们坚信这个剧本的潜力 我们相信Vince
And they said we really believe in this,we really believe in Vince
我们相信这个剧本会成为一流的电视剧
And we feel that this can be a very terrific show
然后我说 嘿伙计们 这是你们自己的事业
And I said hey guys,this is your career,
如果你们真的觉得这个有那么棒的话 那就做下去吧
If you really think that this is that great,you should go ahead with it
我不能说 还会有哪个台的头头会那样说
I can't say that any other studio head would've said that
我真的要在这儿赞一下AMC
And it's a great compliment in this place
我真不确定 这剧放到其他哪个台能成
I'm not sure the show was anywhere else would have actually made it into the air
在我们为《绝命毒师》选角之前
Before we started on Breaking Bad
我们刚刚为拉霍亚剧场完成选角任务
We had just finished casting for the La Jolla Playhouse
Bryan Cranston来为主角试读台词 我们都被他的表现震惊了
And Bryan Cranston came in to read for the lead role and blew us away
对于Walter White这角色 他有着360度的完美素质
Bryan Cranston has the full 360 that you need for somebody like Walter White
他们是绝配
It was the perfect match
所以当我们去找Vince谈一些想法时
So when we went to talk to Vince about some ideas
我们对Bryan Cranston是赞不绝口
We couldn't stop talking about Bryan Cranston
而他恰巧是Vince开始选角时 脑中设想的那个演员
Who was the actor that Vince had had in mind when he was starting to cast
所以那是一次心有灵犀般的交流
So it was a meeting of the minds
Vince的支持是很重要的 因为你去一个电视台说
And it was really helpful because when you go to a network
你有一个新的剧情类电视剧的创意
And you say for your brand new series drama
却想要《马尔科姆的一家》中的爸爸来主演
We wanted to cast the dad from Malcom In The Middle
你可以想象你会得到啥反应
You can imagine the reaction you would get
我觉得 这剧本就是个精彩绝伦的文学作品
I thought,this is an incredible piece of literature
我非常想参演 让我的气味遍布这个角色
I wanted to go in there and spray my scent all over that character
我想要做个标记将它据为己有
I wanted to mark it as mine
以至于让Vince回头再看这个角色时
So that when Vince Gilligan even look back at the character
他都能闻到我的麝香
He could smell my...my musk
还要说 不知怎的 Bryan你好像从纸上冒出来了
and go I don't know why,Bryan,you coming off the page
但那确实发生了
But that's what happens
首播集的拍摄 导演Vince Gilligan
我们刚到片场时 大家好像很快就契合在一起了
When we walked on set,everyone just sort off jelled
以一种非常完美 非常独特的方式
In such a perfect unique way
Bryan和我之间 自第一天起就有一种化学反应
And Bryan and I had this chemistry from day one
让我们默契十足
That just really worked
很快你能意识到 这个项目里的人们真的是超一流的
Very quickly,you begin to realize that the people connected to the project were really first rate
我们有两次奥斯卡奖得主John Toll 他是我们的摄像指导
We had john toll who had won two Oscars,he was the cinematographer
所以有很多人打来电话要求为我们免费工作
So there were people calling us up offering to work for free
只为了能在John Toll的团队里
Just to be on a john toll crew
我记得在To'Hajiilee时
I remember out in To'Hajiilee
一个非常寒冷的早上 我快冻死了
It was a quite chilling morning,I wimped out
我将Bryan拉到一边对他说
And I said to Bryan,I took him aside and said
你穿着内裤感觉怎么样
How do you feel about the underpants
他说 你知道吗 你觉得我能穿的最尴尬的东西是什么
He said,you know what  what's the most embarrassing thing I could be dressed in
我说紧身内裤
I said tighty-whity underpants
他说那就是我要穿的 因为那样对角色来说是对的
He said that's what I'm gonna wear,because that's what's right for the character
我想把自己塑造成 一个臃肿的不修边幅的人 一个对生活失望的人
I intended to be over-weight,I wanted to be a guy,who went to seed,who didn't care any more
第一集里有场戏 我要从房车里跳下来
So popping out of that RV in the pilot episode
观众们可以看到我内裤上面一堆赘肉
And having my love handles fold over my tighty-whity underwear
那可不是我真的想呈现给世界的样子
It wasn't the image that I really would like to present to the world
但是不管怎样 你需要鼓起勇气这样去做
And yet,you had to have the courage to do so
我们在沙漠腹地里拍摄的时候
In the middle of the desert shooting of the show
他就只穿个内裤 在那里跳来舞去
He was dancing around in his underwear
然后我心里想 噢上帝啊 我爱这个男人
And I just thought to myself,my god,I love this man
谁知道我们的男一号会这么有意思
The idea of that number 1 on the call-sheet would be able to have so much fun
而且我们也可以不怎么把他当回事
And not taking him so seriously all the time
特别是当我们拍一个异常紧张的场景时 这是一件美妙的事
Particularly when we are doing such intense scenes,was a wonderful thing
卡
Cut
非常幸运的是 当我们第一次放映第一集的时候
Luckily the first time we had a screening of the pilot episode
我就知道Sony和AMC喜欢它了
I knew already that SONY liked it and AMC liked it
我记得Josh Sapen说过 如果将试播集延长20分钟
I remember Josh Sapen say,did you know if you added 20 minutes to that
那一集可能会成为年度最佳独立电影
That pilot is probably the best independent film of the year
我们在SONY试播了这一集 是给演职人员们看的
But we had a screening at SONY,and it was for the cast and crew
很谦虚地说 这一集的完美让所有人都充满了敬畏之情
In the most modest way possible,we are just in such awe of how beautiful it looked
导演的手法简直绝了
Just the way it was directed
我们爆发了雷鸣般的掌声和欢呼 我们是那么自豪 完全被征服了
We all just started roaring and applauding,we were so proud,we are so blown away
我当时完全不能相信 自己会是这部剧的一部分
And I thought I can't believing I'm part of this
那会儿我仍不理解 这个故事怎么能被拍成电视剧呢
I still didn't understand how this thing would be turned into a television series
我仍然不明白Vince的脑子里在想些什么
And I still didn't understand what was in Vince's head
所以我没法说 我只看了一集试播集 就说了啊 太棒了
So,no I honestly cannot tell you that I looked at the pilot and said oh,my god,eureka
但你明白 这是事实
You know that's the thing
那些看了试播集的人们的疑惑之一是
One of the things that concern people when they saw the finished pilot
他们会说这太棒了 不过它到底在讲什么呢
They said this is great,but what's the show
我不确定Vince或我们其他任何编剧
I'm not sure that Vince,or any of us
真正知道这个电视剧究竟是讲什么的
really know what the show was
我们只知道自己刚开了个头
We knew what we've set up
想着 天啊 如今咱们可一定要完成它了
I was like oh my god,now we've gotta finish it
拍摄《绝命毒师》是一场非常狂野的旅行
The journey of Breaking Bad was a wild ride
我们并不知道走进了什么世界
We didn't know what we are going to get into
第一季播出了 我们向世界呈现了7集
Season 1 we go on the air,we got 7 episodes to show the world
从最初的9集减少了两集 这是因为当年的编剧罢工
Down from 9 because of the writer strike
如果你好奇第一季为啥只有7集
If you are wondering why there are only 7 episodes of the season 1 of Breaking Bad
那是因为那年发生了编剧罢工
That's because there was a writer strike that year
但Vince还是想出了一个在7集里完结的办法
Vince figured out a way to make it a complete season in 7 episodes
我们最初只有很少的观众 我的感觉就是 啥 有没有搞错
We had very few viewers,to me it was like,what?come on
怎么没有更多的人看呢
Why aren't more people watching the show
发现这剧连当年的谷歌搜索排行榜都没上 我当时就震惊了
And I was a little bit dumbfounded that it didn't seem to be registering at all in the Zeitgeist
收视率一般般 但也有一小拨坚定的追随者
Very moderate ratings very small,but mighty following
Dean当时正在和我讨论收视率的事 他问我看了没
Dean was talking about our ratings and he asked me if I looked at that
我说没有 因为我想 你能怎么办呢
And I said,no,because,I was like,what are you gonna do
表演的更好些  你知道 我在尝试了
Act harder  well you know,I'm kind of trying
但如果真的需要收视率的话 我会真的非常努力的
But if we need more numbers,I'm really gonna focus
万分感谢影视评论家和专栏记者们
Thank goddess for the TV critics and the journalists
因为他们喜欢我们这剧 我们必须感谢他们
Because they liked us and I had to give them a lot of credit
因为他们在早期的大力支持 我们才能继续播下去
They really did keep us on the air in those early days
我听说我们没有差评 我们没有一个差评
I was told there are no bad reviews,we didn't have a bad review
第一季以Bryan赢得艾美奖剧情类最佳男主角为高潮
And that first season culminated with Bryan Cranston winning the Emmy for best actor in a drama
然后突然之间 人们突然开始说
And then all of a sudden it seems like people start going
慢着 这个《绝命毒师》是个什么剧
Oh wait a second what's this Breaking Bad
第二季 我们的首要目标就是拍一季完整的
In season 2,we got our first goal at a whole season
第二季的时候我们会因为Walt和Jesse的对手戏而异常激动
By season 2 we all got really excited about having Walt and Jesse scenes
就好像慢慢成了两个主角的剧
It kinda felt like it was turning into a two-hander
换句话说 这剧很大程度上是关于Walter的
In another words,the show is very much about Walter White
但是渐渐地也变成了Jesse的剧
But it's also becoming very much about Jesse Pinkman
Michael Slovis在第二季的时候加入了我们
Michael Slovis started with us in season 2
在视觉方面他把本片推上了更高的一层楼
And I think very much elevated the show in terms of its look
氛围更加黑暗 人物故事更加如履薄冰
He made it even darker,even edgier
第二季带来了Bob和Jonathan
It brought the arrival of Bob Odenkirk and Jonathan Banks
整个剧在不断演进 故事变得越来越庞大
The show was evolving and it was getting bigger
第三季则更加黑暗了
Season 3 gets a little bit darker
一开始观众看到的 就是两个穿着体面的冷血杀手兄弟
Viewers introduced to the well dressed cousins who turn out to be very dangerous
在第三季的时候 我才感觉我们的剧真真正正的开始腾飞了
By the time we get to season 3 I began to feel our little show had really taken flight
第三季结束后 时代周刊发布了
At the end of season 3,TIME magazine published
过去一年里电视剧中的优秀单集前十名
The top 10 episodes of television in the previous year
Michelle Maclaren执导的《一分钟》那一集就是第一名
And the Michelle Maclaren's One Minute was the number 1 show
当Gus加入进来时 我们达到了一个之前完全没想到的高度
When Gus Fring came in,we are now doing this on a level that was not possible to foresee
Giancarlo诠释了一个电视史上最足智多谋的反派形象
Giancarlo Esposito brought the most intense villain in history of television
大规模制毒和超级实验室的想法出现了
Mass producing and the idea of a super lab
那个超级制毒实验室绝对是一个转折点 视觉上的 情节上的
The lab was definitely a turning point,visually,physically
第三季还特别是小粉失去清白的转折点
Season 3 was really the loss of innocence for Jesse in particular
在第三季结束时他开枪杀了那个化学家
The very last moment of season 3 was him pulling the trigger
从而验证了自己的确是个坏人
And proving he was the bad guy
艾美提名捷报不断 Bryan和Aaron都因第三季的表现拿奖了
The Emmy noms continued and Bryan won for season 3 Aaron won for season 3
非常激动人心 这是他们完美合作的最好明证
Which was very exciting and I think a real validation of that partnership
三连折桂艾美 真正让人们开始谈论起了《绝命毒师》
These 3 Emmys in a row really had people talking about Breaking Bad
特别是之前还没听说过的那些人
People who otherwise might not have known about the show
直到第三季开播以后
It wasn't until about after season 3 had aired
才有不少的观众都在看了
That was like oh,there was quite a few people that watched the show
这部剧的成功开始显露了
The success of the show was becoming apparent
Vince和《绝命毒师》第三季都获得了作家指南奖
Vince won and the show won for season 3 for the writers guild awards
Stephen King将它称作史上最好的剧之一
Stephen king called it,one of the greatest show of all time
Bryan和Aaron上了《滚石》的封面
Bryan and Aaron appeared on the cover of rolling stone
神呐 这得是多高的曝光度啊
And man,what a highlight that was
然后 第四季变得越来越危险了
And then,by season 4,it got incredibly dangerous
现在 全都是关于老白的自负 面子 贪婪和权力欲
Now,it's all about his ego,and being respected,and greed and power
每一季都有更多的观众 更多的奖项
Each season,more people are watching the show,more awards
更多的关注 而且评论界也是持续看好
More attention,the reviews continued to be wonderful
我想那就是为什么Vince好像在说 嘿 我们可不想一直霸占头条
And I think that's part of why Vince was like hey we do not want to overstay our welcome
我赢了
I won
现在我们走到了第五季
So now we get to season 5
不幸的是 在我的编剧团队的帮助下我意识到
Unfortunately,I came to realization with the help of my writers
我们只有16集左右的故事可以拍了
That we had about only 16 or more episodes of story left to us
Vince一开始就说了他准备在这剧表现良好的时候结束
Vince said from the beginning that he wanted to end the show when it's doing well
而他现在只有这么多集剩下了
And that he only had only so many episodes
这并不是一个容易的决定 但是在某种程度上 我知道必须要完结了
It's not an easy decision to make,but at a certain point,I knew it had to end
冒一点风险 结束的早总比结束太晚更好
I know it's better to risk ending it a bit too soon than to end too late
《绝命毒师》编剧办公室 2012年12月
作为整部剧的制作人 我最重要的工作是首席编剧
My most important job as a show runner of Breaking Bad is head writer
我要做的最重要的事
That the most important thing I do
就是带领着编剧工作室 并确保把故事讲好
Is run the writer's room and ensured the story gets told
我只是觉得之前我们讨论时
I just feel like there's..when we were talking about it last week
剧情深化之前还有很多家庭关系要理清楚
I feel like there's was a lot about family before it actually takes off
比如 说真的 因为马上就要拍这几集了
Like what  I'm serious because I'm too close to it right now
写最后一段剧情是一个挑战 部分是因为大家真的很爱我们剧
Breaking the final leg was a challenge,partially because people do love the show
所以我们真的想好好回馈大家
And we really wanted to pay it off
Skyler必须为了她的孩子保持坚强
She has to remain strong for her kids
要不就是她彻底崩溃无法再坚强起来
Or else she just so devastated that she can't remain strong any more
也是因为我们剧在评论界美誉连连 我们更加压力山大
There was a lot of pressure because also the show has been critically acclaimed
那逼着我们想创意到想到发晕
And that can create a sense of creative vertigo
Walt Jr 这条故事线也得发生点什么
Something you need to transpire with Junior
这样才可能会导致接下来的事情的发生
that forces...perhaps forces this issue
有如此多的拼图我们要将它们环环相扣
There were so many of these puzzle pieces that we sort of wanted to lock together
有两种可能 要么他们和他一起走
There are two possibilities,they can leave town and come with him or
要么他们分道扬镳
They can leave town,and go somewhere completely different
我们想要成为那种为数不多的剧 不狗尾续貂
We wanted to be one of the few shows that ended like we begin
你知道 就是超牛逼的那种
Which was you know,kicking ass
最终季摄制首日 Q片场 阿尔伯克基
开始我们最后一程的工作时 我的心情很是复杂
I feel a mixture of things being here at the beginning of this last push
我现在倒不会感到很怀旧 你可能会那样想
I don't feel as nostalgic right now as you might expect
我主要是感到的是紧张 我是个多愁善感的人
I feel mainly nervous,I'm very sentimental person,
当一切结束时 我会超级想念这个剧
I'm gonna miss this mightily when it's over
我想这部剧的每个工作人员都理解 这部剧需要高调谢幕
I think everybody working on Breaking Bad understands the need to end the show on a high note
我当然不希望它结束 我希望它一直继续下去
I don't want it to end,I want it to go on forever
可能最重要的原因 在我看是
Probably the most important reason for that,for me,is that
我们已经成了一个大家庭
We've created a family here
兄弟 一切可好
-brother,how is everything going
你啥时候来的
-when did you get in the town
昨天三点半 -真棒
-yesterday at 3.30 -nice
快结束了 太难受了
Oh the end is near,so sad
我们在很棒的Q片场 准备预读第五季第九集的剧本
We are at the fantastic Q studios and we are about to do the table read of S5E09
这是第五季第二部分的第一集
Our first episode back in season 5B
瞧啊
-look at this
你怎么样 见到你真好
-how are you,good to see you
每一季开拍的时候 我感觉就好像回到了大本营
I felt every season like you get to go back to camp
你等不及要和朋友们团聚
And you can't wait to go and you can't wait see your friends
所有人都将团聚在一起
And everybody is gonna come back
Anna Gunn  哟
Anna Gunn  everybody
你怎么样亲爱的 -我很好 你真美
How are you,honey -I'm good,you look beautiful
我们相处得很好 而Bryan好像是领袖
The way we all approached it,it were sort of led by Bryan
让我们好好珍惜品味我们在一起的每一份每一秒
Let's savor and relish every second that we have together and let's enjoy every last minute of it
因为我们是这么幸运能拥有这一切
Because we are so lucky to have this
很高兴见到你 -你开车来的吗
Nice to see you -did you drive or
不 我昨天乘飞机来的
No,I flew,yesterday
在我们开始之前 请Gilligan先发言
Before we start anything,I hand it over to Mr.Gilligan
欢迎大家回来 这是我们最后一次开拍前预读会议
Everybody welcome,to our final pre-production table read
这集超赞 是由Peter Gould执笔的 他在哪 -他读Badger的部分
For this wonderful episode that,where's Peter,that Peter Gould wrote -he's reading Badger
这一集由Bryan Cranston执导
And this episode directed by Mr. Bryan Cranston
《绝命毒师》第五季第九集 染血的钱
Episode of Breaking Bad titled blood money episode 509
为什么是Keylee
Why Kaylee Ehrmantraut
她需要一个人照顾她
She needs someone to look after her
Mike完全有能力照顾他的小孙女
Mike is more than capable of taking care of his own granddaughter
参与读稿试演感觉很棒
It's amazing to sit in a read-through
大家分开了差不多四五个月
With those who have been away for a hiatus for 4 or 5 month
看着这些超棒的演员坐下来
And to watch these brilliant actors sit down and
高超地表演这些台词
Do these worlds,embrace these worlds
好似他们过去五个月都在故事里生活着
As if they were living in them everyday for the last 5 months
如果Mike还活着 你接下来都要担惊受怕
If Mike were out there you'll have to look over your shoulder for the rest of your life
那不是你做事的风格
That's not how you do things
我认为他已经死了 而且你知道这一点
I think he is dead and I think you know that
先上收敛水 对吧
Astringent goes on first
我脸上那丁点的水分也要没了
So any moisture that I happened to have in my face is gone
我就知道Bryan是最适合演Walter的人
I knew Bryan is the right guy,to play Walter White,I knew he was the man for the role
所以现在我们要做的 就是使他看上去更老一些 更沧桑一些
So what we are doing here is trying to age him,and decay him,somewhat
可怜的Walt
Poor Walt
他唤醒这个角色的方式 诠释这个角色的方式
The way he arose the occasion,to play this part,this character
都是令人惊艳的 他很在乎这个角色的一切
Is stunning,he cares deeply about this character and
对于每个细节都精益求精
Getting details of this character right
他注定要演这个角色 在我心中 这就是命运
He was meant to play this part,it was fate,it was destiny,in my mind
Bryan是一个彻底不同于Walt的人
Bryan is a completely different person than Walt
当他换上Walt的皮肤 上了妆之后
And when he put on that skin,when he puts on the make up
他就变成了Walt 而且是一场真正的变形
He transforms into Walt white,and it's a true transformation
从一个热爱生活的 本质上非常乐观和幸福的一个人
From a man who loves life,and who is naturally very happy and optimistic
转变成了内心黑暗 很具破坏性的Walt
To Walt,who has so much darkness and so much damage
他们是如此的不同
The two could not be more distinct
我从一开始就看到了Walt生命的动态走向
I realized that the dynamic aspect of Walt white from the very beginning
现在是时候说再见了
And now it's the time to say goodbye
他是一个被打倒的人
He was a beaten-down man
虽然已经身形憔悴 他仍然能专注于手边的任务
And even in his physical depletion he was able to focus on the task at hand
托起颧骨会使得脸颊看起来下陷了
By building up the cheekbones,it appears as if you are hollowing out cheeks
高颧骨会让我看上去更瘦
Build this up I'll look thinner,like I've lost weight
这个火鸡一样的脖子
And this of course the turkey neck
会让他看起来短时间内掉了很多斤
Makes it like he's lost a lot of weight,in a short period of time
由于电视剧每集分开制作的模式
Because of the way episodic television was produced
每一集我们都会有不同的导演
We've had different directors for each episode
有时是嘉宾导演 有时是我 有时是Vince
Sometimes it's a guest director,sometimes it's me,sometimes it's Vince Gillian
有时是我们编剧之一 有时是我们的摄像指导Mike Slovis
Sometimes it's one of our writers,sometimes it's our cinematographer Mike Slovis
有时是Bryan Cranston
And sometime it's Bryan Cranston
在准备过程中 我最喜欢的一个发现就是
One of my favorite things that I discovered in the prep
Walt家被毁的很惨
Was the destruction of the White house
而我第一眼看到那被摧毁的样子后感到很沮丧
and that how depressing that was to see it first time
看到Walt家的那种情况就好像是 你踏过的是一片坟墓
It's almost like trampling on a grave when you look at the white house in that condition
《绝命毒师》有两位老爸
We have two dads on Breaking Bad
一位是Bryan 另一个是Mike Slovis
One of them was Bryan Cranston one of them is Mike Slovis
他是我们的摄像指导
Mike Slovis is our cinematographer
他负责所有的摄影和画面工作
As such he is responsible for all things photographic on the series
我提出来是因为 这样拍摄的话 你的背景是一堵白墙
The only reason I say,is because,this is you against a flat wall
关于摄像指导 人们常说
It's often been said about cinematographers
你要么拍的好 要么拍的快 但你不可能两者兼得
You either get good,or you get fast,but you never get both
而Michael却是那种少见的能兼顾二者的大师
Michael Slovis is the rare cinematographer who is both great and he's fast
你们两个都看我演示
Watch me from both,because
你走到这里
So you come in
这里切成主人公视角 -对 切成主人公视角
We got the POV,-I got the POV
这之后再切回你继续前进 这样可以拍到有更有趣的背景
Now you go and you have a really interesting background
-还有人物的反应 -比对着一面白墙拍要好
-and I get your reaction -as opposed to this
从一开始
At the very beginning
我和Vince对于这部戏的配色走向 就有一个大致的计划
Vince and I had a plan of where the entire series should go in terms of pallet and color
当Walt越来越堕落成一个罪恶的人
As Walt descended more into this really evil being
我让这个剧的色调变得越来越黑暗
I saw the show getting darker and darker and darker
有这么好的剧本 我能用更大的画笔作出更宏大的作品
With materials this great,I can paint with a bigger brush,
因为故事强大到足以支持那样的场面
Because it can support it
这就是我们正在做的工作
So this is what we are doing now,
用Heisenberg本人的视角来拍摄 他走入废墟旧宅的过程
Is the POV of Heisenberg walking down his old burnt-down life
我是Andrew Voegeli A机位摄像
My name is Andrew Voegeli,and I am the A-camera operator on Breaking Bad
拍摄了第二季至第五季下部分
From season 2 through season 6
这样的大制作 从头到尾每天的摄制工作都非常累人
Breaking Bad being hell of a show,it's just a grueling process,you know,from start to finish everyday
拍摄这部电视剧对体力要求很高
So physically it's a very demanding show,and very..very hard
卡
And.. And we cut
拍第五季第九集的第一天 我们为下一集开了一次概念研讨会
The first day that we were shooting 509,we did a concept meeting for episode 510
大家好么
How are u guys doing
我们把剧情卡片贴墙上了 -好的 不错
We're putting our cards on board -alright good
等你们回来 再看看还剩几个点子没毙掉
We'll see how many survive when you get back
我们在为第五季第十集做准备 这集是Tom Schnauze写的
We're prepping for E510,which was written by tom Schnauze
Tom可以说是我的老朋友了
And tom is arguably my oldest friend
1986年 我们在纽约大学蒂诗艺术学院的电影系结识
We met in 1986 at Tisch school of the arts at NYU,the film school
剧本写的超赞 爱你们
Great job on the scripts,very great yeah..thank you  great writing,I love you.
Diana 我们讨论了下 有没有可能拍摄一些背部视角的镜头
Diana there has been some conversations about doing some via-backs potentially here,for the point of view
90年代末拍《X档案》的时候我认识了Michelle
I met Michelle back in the late 1990s on the X-files….
他去我们看的地方了
He went down the neighborhoods that we were looking at
视觉上非常棒 而且还都有栅栏
Which was visually fantastic and all have fences
每次她来导演一集的时候 我都能放下心来
Every time she sets up to direct an episode of Breaking Bad,I can relax quite a bit
我知道她会关注到所有重要的问题
Because I know she is gonna ask all the questions that needed get asked
我是觉得 你和Bryan的那集没必要用不一样的景
It seems to me that there's no reason for you to a different neighborhood your episode and Bryan's
但是 那片没有栅栏之类的东西
So..not having the fences and things…
Vince的优点在于 他是个很本色的人
The great thing about Vince,is that Vince doesn't change
他爱这个片场 又有领导力
He loves his set,a great tone for everybody
他会说我们要有专业人员的样子 但也要有乐子
You know let's endorse how's professional,but let's have some fun
任务重大 我们来好好干吧 这就是我们的工作方式
We've got a lot of work ahead of us,that's do great work..that's our approach
Tom 你是想穿着工装背带裤里面还不穿衣服吗
Tom,do you man,do you wanna dress like you are in the barrel overall and no-shirt look
把书拿在这
This is down here
第一幕 Dean从厕所里走出来的时候
When Dean Norris comes out of bathroom,the very first act
他要承担着惊天发现的重压
He is carrying the weight of discovery on the shoulders
关于怎么演 我们有好几个想法
There was a variety of different ideas on how to play that
观众们都在想
The audiences are wondering
如今Hank从厕所里出来该是什么想法 他会怎么做
Now what is hank gonna feel when he comes out of that bathroom,what's he gonna do
我认为 Hank的心理活动应该是 我该怎么说 就说我肚子不舒服
The process to me is..what should I say ..just say I'm not feeling well
然后你的视线来找我 屋角的镜头打过来
And you are looking after me,camera around the corner
因为你拿着那本书 所以赶紧把它藏在后面
Cuz' you got that book you are about ready to put that book behind your back
我觉得剧情很棒 Hank追踪了那么久 终于要抓到这条白鲸了
I think it's great that hank is gonna get to finally catch the white whale that he's been chasing
单单凭这本书 所有的一切都连结起来 昭示着不幸的事实
You know all this lone book..and then after that all help brings them unfortunately
56秒 开拍
56 secs,and action
还可以怎么拍 还有其他的想法吗
Anything you would do differently  either one of you
这时的Hank要想 Walt在哪呢
Right now,he is thinking where is Walt..
可以是 他整个人好像僵了一样 大脑发懵
One way he's just almost like zombified.. Like he's in his hell head
自己往哪走都不清楚了 这一切都说得通吗
Just not even know where he is going..does that make any sense
很多剧情分析都是在拍摄的每分每秒进行的
Lots of analysis goes into every single moment of Breaking Bad
Bryan做导演的时候 他对编剧们的建议相当开放
And when Bryan Cranston is directing,he is so open to notes from writers
我一直很欣赏他这一点
I always impressed by that
但是Hank也要留神提防Walt进来
But he has the awareness to look out for Walt coming in
我认为他走到起居室时 是可以听见你的
I would say when he gets to the living room,he could hear you
或者是厨房那边 -他不时地能听见你
Or he'd be in the kitchen there -he could hear you at some point
只要稍微像这样 明白吗 -好的
But in...till end it's just like,alright,you know -OK
Dean 这个镜头再试一次彻底懵掉的Hank
So Dean,try one where you dumbstruck by this
下半身在走 上面胳膊摆在头上
Sometimes part of you is walking,part of you is up here
作为导演一定要认识到 整个剧组是协作性质的
You have to embrace the collaborative nature that it is
否则就麻烦了
And if you don't you are gonna be in trouble
要么大家认为你太独裁 不愿意跟你工作
Either people would hate work with you because you are dictatorial
只能以我的方法行事 这种想法是行不通的
Like my way is the only way kind of thing,and that's just not true
我必须要参考各种各样的意见
You have to allow for a variety of different opinions
深呼吸....往前走
Take deep breath..and go
卡
And cut -cutting
我觉得就是这样的一种合作精神造就了《绝命毒师》
I think that level of collaboration is what makes Breaking Bad work
让每一个场景都成为精品
It what makes this individual scene work
Dean 你觉得这次怎么样
How do you feel about that Dean
-不错 -有区别吗
Alright good. -any different
-老实说的确是不同了
It's a honestly a different thing
-喜欢吗 -我觉得非常好
Got three of them,do you like that'  I think that was great
-我非常喜欢
I really like it
他们思路相当快 能够把我脑子里的
They think so quickly,and able to take the idea,
某些的有趣想法迅速地转换为现实
That something tickles me,turning into a concrete result so fast
这就是快乐之处
That's really that's the fun of it
这是剧组的劳模
This is the hardest working person on the crew here
Helen Caldwell 本片场记
Helen Caldwell,she was our script supervisor
她自己就是一个部门
She is a department of one
所以每次开各部门会议 她都要到场
So when they have department meetings,she has to be there
我们是做记录的 包括拍摄的过程 资料打印事宜
We keep track of stuff..keep track of every shot..what get printed what doesn't
演员们站起来说了哪些话
What line will say when they stood up and move..
又停在哪一句上了 往左转了还是往右转了
What word did they stop on,did they turn it right or left..
演员们要是漏词了 我就得上前去告诉他 你搞砸了
Any actors drop a line,I would actually go in there and tell him: You screwed up
她真的是这样 她会走过来这样说 你是故意不说这句的
Yeah she will come in and go Did you want to drop this line,was that a choice or
-还是失误了 -然后我就哎呀……
Boo-boo..you know,I'd go: Ah…
自第一集后 第五季第九集最后的对峙场景就是我们最期待的
The final conversation in S5E09 is something we've been waiting for ever since the end of the pilot
自从Walt决定成为罪犯
Ever since Walt decided to become a criminal
把自己放在Hank的瞄准镜下之后
and therefore put himself in his brother-in-law's gun sights,
这就是我们等待的时刻
This is it,this is the moment
大致就是这样 抡上来....
So the idea is....come in
和兼任导演的演员合作是有些不同之处的
There is a little bit of difference to working with the lead actor that's the director as well
真是有些伤脑经 因为他有想法 他知道怎么做最好
It makes a little more nerve-racking,cuz' he got his vision he knows exactly what he wants
你不想让他受伤 但又得给他最好的效果
You want to keep him safe but you also want to give him what he is looking for
然后你推他 把情势拉回到中立 然后在那一刹那出手 这样画面就很棒了
And then you push,bring it back down to neutral but just that split second it looks great
再往这边来一点 划个圆 -对
Come here more  A circle -yeah
这一场戏我要打Bryan 打Walter White
This is the scene where I actually hit Bryan,hit Walter White
这是个出其不意的拳头
When he doesn't know that I am actually gonna hit him
开拍
Action
没事吧 说真的 我不喜欢你那个眼神
You OK  I gotta say I don't like the way you are looking at me right now
其实真实打架的情形
You know like most fights are
都不是好莱坞式的纠缠不清的假斗
It doesn't go on and on and on,fake Hollywood style,slugging and slugging
而是一个拳头下去 应声倒地 然后就完事了 又快又狠
It's usually one hit and boom  then it's over,it's violent and quick'
是你这个混蛋 你撞车不让我去洗衣厂
You you drove into traffic to keep me away from that laundry
打电话骗我Marie受伤住院
That call I got from Marie said she was in the hospital
不是Pinkman搞的鬼 你有我手机号码
That wasn't Pinkman. You had my cell
我很惊喜在表演中看到了Hank的痛苦
I was so happily surprised that pain that comes out in hank's expression,
他因为被背叛的愤怒以及煎熬
His demeanor he is angry as hell,he is betrayed. He is in agony.
你居然杀了十个证人 炸了养老院
You killed ten witnesses,you bombed a nursing home.
他不打算打我了 但他抓着我的头
He is not gonna hit me again,but he is like,he grabs the hold of my head
因痛苦而颤抖 真是令人心碎
Vibrating with this anguish,oh  it's just really heartbreaking
你要是真的不知道我是谁 那你最好小心点
If you don't know who I am,then maybe your best course is to tread lightly
卡
Cut it
第五季 第十集 《地面之下》
导演:Michelle Maclaren 编剧:Thomas Schanauz
第五季第十集 我们有了一辆制毒巴士 由Mark S Freeborn设计
S05E10 we got this meth lab bus,mark S freeborn designed it for us.
这里是第五季上部分里Todd带来的设备
This is the equipment from the first half of season 5,that Todd took
用的正是Vamonos杀虫公司用的移动装备
Right this is the same equipment that we use in the mobile Vamonos pest control set up
他们和Todd做了交易就把这个带走了 Walt脱离了这个业务
They made a deal with Todd,so they went and Walt bailed from the business
Hells Angels:地狱天使帮是世界上非同小可的现代犯罪组织
Mark像是圣诞老人和狂野凶狠的飞车族的混合体
Mark is mix between Santa Clause and hells angels biker
在一大群幕前幕后工作人员中
In a show populated by characters in front of and behind the lens
他是出类拔萃的一个
Mark is a character par excellence
很多道具化学品都可以用厨房搅拌机制作
Lot of the elements are found,you can use a kitchen mixer to mix chemicals
所有的东西都必须能通过 我们面前这个30英寸的舱门
Everything has to fit through the a 30 inch hole where the trap door is in front of us
整体的效果是为了把凸显这里的阴暗 险恶 肮脏 令人不适
The overall effect is to create a sinister,shadowy,uncomfortable,unsanitary environment
与Walt和Jesse的 卫生又安全的大实验室形成对比
Compared to Walt and Jesse's very sanitary,very safe,very clean meth lab
不可思议 他们做了很细节的东西 所有的窗户都必须是树脂玻璃的
It's fantastic,he has done the details,all the windows has to be plexi
他们在窗户上做涂鸦
Uh..what they have done is they did graffiti on the windows
在树脂玻璃后面铺上灰尘
So we have the dirt,is held in the plexi behind the window..
他们准备好了吗
Are they ready for me or not
Laura 开拍后 我会指示灰尘落下来
So laura,I am gonna say on action,I'm gonna cue the dirt to come down,
我会模拟子弹的声音 我们估计要做好几次
Then I gonna say bullet all right  then we will probably do that a couple of times
Michelle拍的动作戏是我见过最好的
Michelle Maclaren directs action better than anyone I have worked with
她第一次看剧本的时候 这段画外的枪战场景快把她逼疯了
This shoot-out happens off camera,and that kind of drove Michelle crazy when she read it
为什么不把枪战拍出来 她说
She said,why can we see shootout
我说 这场戏不能这样拍
I said cuz' that's not the way we want to do this one,
因为这段我们想用Lydia的视角来叙事
We want to play this through the point of view Lydia Rodarte-Quayle
她在地下 而枪战在她头顶上发生
As she heard the gunfire going on above her
她说 能不能就拍一点点
She says,yeah can we see a little bit of it
可以剪掉其他的... 就拍一丁点点...
Can we cut away the...just a little ...can we see a little little bit
我说 不行...
And I say no..
扔弹壳 梆梆
Shell  Bang bang
我最喜欢Michelle的一点就是
One of the many things I love about Michelle is
就算她尽力控制自己
Even when she is reined in,
她还是会对那些戏份精益求精 亮出狮吼功
She would still find a way to milk those moments and hit those high notes
落尘土
Dirt
低下头 警惕地抬起头 看着弹壳
Put your head down,look up alert,look at the shell
梆
Bang
我们并不是在真的巴士上 我们是在一个舞台上
We weren't on a bus,we were on a stage
而且头顶也没有一场真实的枪战
And there was not really a shoot-out up above
演员们则是孤身一人身处场景之中
But the actor is in the scene by themselves
所以你会想要帮助她们创造一个利于发挥的背景
And you want to help create the setting
总不能毫无生气地说灰尘 子弹 邦邦邦吧
You don't wanna go dirt,bullets,bang bang bang
因为那样对演员发挥很不好
Cuz it's not very good for the actors
看子弹 低下头 邦邦邦
look to the bullets,look to the bullets,and head down,bang bang bang
看舱口
And hatch
所以我会完全投入其中 大叫着邦邦邦 因为那就是正在发生的啊
So I get in to into it,I was like bang bang bang,that's what's happening up there
卡 很棒 你们真不错 多谢大家 非常好
Cut it,good stuff,thank you guys that's great
Laura 你可以回家好好泡个脚舒缓一下了
Laura,you can go home and soak your feet
能上这个剧 我真的有点战战兢兢的
I was really intimidated to come on
但又非常高兴能得到一个如此棒的角色
But at the same time,so delighted to get such an amazing part
所幸的是 我能全身心投入其中
Luckily I just dive into that character
本集 Laura的部分结束
Episode wrap-up on laura
虽然这个布景只用上两分半钟
Despite the fact that the set has been on camera for a grand total of two and a half minutes
但是这是链条上不可或缺的一环 使得故事顺利的被讲述
It's a link in a chain,it tells a story
而一个好故事一定是完整的链条
And the best story-telling is what completes a chain
两分半上镜时间确实少 谁在乎呢 每一秒都值得
So two and a half minutes of screen time,who cares,it's worth every second
好了伙计们 第一场要开始了 安静点
OK guys first scene is in,lets get quiet please
人们喜欢谈论《绝命毒师》中那些大场面
People talk about the big moments on Breaking Bad
但是值得讨论的是 这部剧的灵魂和精髓
But it could be argued that the heart of the show
则存在于那些安静的时刻
Is the quieter moments
比如老白在浴室地板上不省人事那场戏
Like the moment in which Walt passed out on the floor of his bathroom
这些角色的安静时刻
These very quiet moments of character
会让我们真正的阐释和理解这些角色 明白他们的信仰
Where we illuminate and understand who these characters really are and what they really believe
那才是本剧的灵魂所在
Are the heart and soul of the show
Anna Gunn是这样一个超棒的演员
Anna Gunn was just a terrific actor to work with
我们之间形成了一个非常亲密的关系 滋养了深厚的友谊
We developed a very close relationship and friendship with each other
以及信任 我们知道 我们会关照对方保护对方
And a trust we knew we would gonna watch each other and protect each other
不仅仅是作为演员 更是作为镜头之外的平凡人
As actors and as people,in a scene and outside the scene
开拍
Action
天 我昏了多久了
Oh god how long was I out
四五个钟头吧
About for 4 or 5 hours
故事开头 Skyler是整个剧的道德中心
Skyler started out as the moral center of the show
她质问别人 慢着 你在干嘛 你不能这么做
And the person saying Wait a sec,what are you doing,you can't do that
而这让观众不开心了
And that made the audience angry
这样你高兴了吗
Does that make you happy
我不记得上次我高兴是什么时候了
I can't remember last time when I was happy
有人说 我恨她 她是个贱人
When somebody says,I hate her,she is a bitch
我会想 等等 你为什么会这么想呢 难道你不明白吗
I think,wait a second,why do you think that,don't you understand
你不能理解她所经历的痛苦吗
Don't you understand what she is going through
我本人会很受伤
And I take it very very personally
我们会发现在每一部剧中
What we figured out is that in every show
都有一个主人公和一个反派
There's a protagonist and there's a antagonist
本剧主人公就是老白 但是他却是一个反英雄式的角色
In the show the protagonist is Bryan,but he is an anti-hero
他做了很多坏事
He is a guy who's doing pretty bad things
Vince从未想过让我演个哭哭啼啼的软弱女人
Vince never ever wanted some soft,hand-wringing,weeping woman
在前几季如果我偶尔泪眼汪汪
If I got teary in the first couple of seasons
他会明确地对我说 不能那样
He specifically would say to me,don't do that
他想让她成为钢铁般无坚不摧的女强人
He wanted her to be steely,really really strong
从一开始就是一个顶梁柱般的强大的人
And a back-bone of steel from the beginning
他对于这一点的要求相当明确
And he was extremely specific about that
你不交出这笔钱 就不能自首
You can't give yourself up without giving up the money.
就是这么回事
That's the way it works
所以我们最好的对策 就是保持沉默
So maybe our best move here,is to just keep quiet
卡 很好
Cut it very nice,check it up please
这个场景之所以那么有力的原因之一就是
One of the reasons why this moment is so powerful is because
编剧们对于Skyler这一角色的塑造和挖掘是一以贯之的
The writers have been so consistent with the characterization of Skyler throughout the series
而Anna勇于坚持这一点
Anna has been brave enough to stay the course
Anna是个非常出色的演员 因为她勇于保持Skyler这个角色的一致性
Anna is a very brilliant actor since she is very brave for staying true to Skyler
第五季 第十一集 《供认》
导演:Michael Slovis 编剧: Gennifer Hutchson
Michael Slovis执导了第五季第十一集
Michael Slovis directed 511
对于他的执导方式 我非常热爱的有两点
There are two things I really love about the way he approaches directing
首先是他对于表演的重视
One of them is his emphasis on performance
看着Michael在片场和演员们深入探讨是个非常棒的事情
Watching Michael come alive when he is dealing with the actors is a wonderful thing
他的指导就是那画龙点睛的一笔
He is that magical touch
就好像这样 我脑子都乱了
When it's like what a fucking thing I'm thinking..
就是那样
Exactly
他会问我话 但是我不啥都想说
He is gonna ask me and I don't wanna say
应该是对于我来说最难的一场戏了吧
One of our hardest scene for me,a little bit
一般情况我都能很快搞定
Usually I get it right away
-这场戏的动作和音量很微妙
-small movements,speak volumes in a scene like this,
确实有点难以把握
That's why,you know,it can be kinda tricky to figure out
我跟她的互动是什么样一种程度  你理解我什么意思吗
You know how much am I gonna engage with her,you know what I'm saying
她脆弱的坐着 而你强势的站着 就要这样一种感觉
To something really nice about her down,you up
就好像她是如此渺小
Like she is looking very so small you know
我现在就觉得挺无力渺小的
I'm feeling pretty small right now
我好的感情戏都是和Betsy一起拍的
All my emotional good scenes are always with Betsy
说真的 跟你一起拍戏很舒坦
So it's very comforting,seriously,by the way
有你陪伴我走过这个拍摄的旅程真好
It's really been nice to have you as the person to get through the stuff
我总是跟Dean说能够演他的荧屏伴侣是我的荣幸
I always told Dean that it's my privilege and honor to play his television wife
现在 我和Betsy都没看过Walt的自首视频
So neither Betsy nor I have seen the Walt confession
我们故意这样做的 决定提前不看
We kinda made a choice,we wanted to see it for the first time
这样的话他们在拍的时候
When they actually film us watching it
我们就能给出第一次看的反应了
So we can have a reaction to it,for the first time
机位就绪 -机位就绪
Set -set
我叫Walter Hartwell White
My name is Walter Hartwell white
我住在新墨西哥州阿尔伯克基
I live at 308 Negra arroyo lane,Albuquerque,New Mexico,
以下是我的坦白
This is my confession
如果你正在看这个录像
If you're watching this tape
我可能已经死了
I'm probably dead...
被我的连襟Hank Schrader谋杀的
Murdered by my brother-in-law,Hank Schrader.
你觉得他把这个给谁看了
Who do you think he's shown this to
没人 这是个威胁
No one.it's a threat
我再步步紧逼的话 他就要这样做了
It's what he will do if I don't back off
我觉得你应该把这个给Ramey看
I think you should show this to Ramey
趁着还来得及
Just get ahead of it
这个录像就是一堆谎言
That video is a bunch of lies,hank
任何了解你的人都能看出来啊
Anybody who knows you will know
我知道 我又不傻 十七万七千
I know,I'm not morons $177,000
他在胡说些什么 Marie
What the hell's he talking about  Marie
卡
Cut it.
你们演的精彩极了
That was beyond wonderful
这个场景非常复杂 感情波动很大
It's complicated scene with a lot of hills and valleys
这些演员都是一流的
These guys were just wonderful
你基本上可以说是最平易近人的工作伙伴了 -是啊 我还最棒的
Basically you are just the easiest person to work with,-yeah,and best
最有才的 -那当然啦 绝对的
And the most gifted. -yeah,absolutely
神呐 他真会说谎
God,he's such a fucking liar man
开拍
Action
Schrader探员 最近是不是又对哪个嫌犯用刑了
Agent schrader.beat any good suspects lately
嘿 高个子和那个更高的
Hey,tall and taller
问问他他和我的客户有什么过节
Ask him his history with my client
上次他俩单独待一起的的时候 他把这个可怜的小伙子打到神志不清了
Last time they were alone together he knocked the poor kid unconscious
所以是要怎样
So what's it gonna be
想把这事搞成像蒙大拿那么大的民权诉讼吗 那样的话乐意为你们效劳
A civil rights lawsuit the size of Montana,'cause I'll oblige you.
我对剧组的邀请毫无防备
I was really blindsided by the invitation to be a part of the show
非常意外 我完全没预料到
It was a shock,a surprise,something I never saw coming
再见了 拳王 护住您的左翼
Oh,so long,Rocky.keep your left up
警探们 请您们先行离开
Detectives,I'm inviting you to leave
第二季的时候我只演了三集  第三季的十三集中我有十集戏份
In season 2 I was in 3 episodes,and in season 3 I was in 10 of 13
甚至到那时候 我也没看过这部剧
And I still hadn't seen the show,even then
像我刚说的 我就没从头看过这部剧
Like I said I didn't watch it from the beginning
所以在我参与的第二季 也就是你们看到的第三季
So in that second season that I did and third season that you see
我不是很清楚剧情到底发生了什么
I didn't know entirely what was going on
或者我谈论的是哪个人 在我演独角戏的时候
Or who I was talking about when I do some of the monologues
特别是当我提到Gus 和其他没有对手戏的角色
Especially when I came to Gus and other characters who are offscreen from me
那些没有对手戏但又确实认识的角色的时候
Who I never interacted but I knew about
所以有时候Bryan会看着我 因为我重音没搞对
So Bryan would look at me sometimes cuz I would have the wrong emphasis
或者我错误地表达了某些事情
Or say something in the wrong way
他就会说Gus就是那个和我合作的那个人 你是认识他的
He'd be like Gus is the guy that I'm working with,you know him
他还会做出这样的表情 说你根本没看过这部剧 是不是
And he will go like this,you haven't watched the show,have you.
然后我就会这样 哈哈哈 但从来没正面回答过
And I go,haha-ah...and I've never answered him
你可以帮我一个忙吗 告诉我你到底怎么了
But will you do me a favor and tell me what is exactly up with you
我让我的人拼死拼活
I got my guys busting their asses
想把Walt的钱给藏起来 不让条子发现
Trying to hide Walt's money from the feds
你却把你的钱往窗外撒
And you're tossing yours out of a window
而我还得从新闻上知道你的雷锋事迹
And I have to hear about it on the news
喜剧的某些方面很难   好的喜剧很难
Certain aspects of comedy are hard,and good comedy is hard
需要努力 但我觉得演好这个简直更难
Take some effort,but I feel like this is harder by a lot
我搞砸了 我没说错吧 我搞砸了三次
I fucked up,am I kidding  fucked up 3 times
我后退太远 还是因为 我没把镜头转过去
I stepped back too far  or I didn't turn the camera
我还编了自己的台词 -是的
And I made up my own lines -right
但这是个问题吗 在《绝命毒师》剧组
But is that a problem here on Breaking Bad
他们喜欢NG吗 能容忍一点吗
Do they like that or not like that yes or no,a little or a lot
他们可不喜欢NG 非常不喜欢
Not even a little
我有时候会觉得 他不认为他值得演这个角色
I sometime got the feeling he does not feel like he deserves this character
但其实 他绝对值得演Saul Goodman
And he absolutely does deserve to play Saul Goodman
因为你知道他很有趣 事实就是这样
Because you know he's funny,and he is,
但他没意识到他已经成为一个多么出色的演员
But when he doesn't seem to realize what a fine dramatic actor he has become
他现在是 一直都是
He is and always was
-你会演好的 你会演好的 -那要到什么时候
-you'll get it you'll get it -at what point
-第八条吧 -我看是第八季吧
By the end of the 8th -by 8th season
-哎呀 你会没问题的
-yeah,you'll be cool
哦 该我了吗 要进去了 太好了
Oh me I gotta be in here that'll be great
Odenkirk,别再搞砸了 好吗
So Odenkirk,don't fuck up
好的 你说对了
Yeah,exactly right
Michael Slovis还有一件很擅长的事 就是选景
The other thing that Michael Slovis does so well is the way he choose his locations
你能从第五季第十一集看出来 Saul,Walt和Jesse见面的那片穹丘
You can see it in 511,the domes where Saul,Walt and Jesse meet
Vince常说他希望《绝命毒师》看起来像个西部片
Vince always said he always saw Breaking Bad to be kind of like a western
当我们在沙漠腹地拍摄的时候
When we were shooting in the middle of the desert
有时候的确像是在拍西部片
It does feel like we are shooting a western at times
今天我们在帕哈里多穹丘 很冷 现在可能只有3度
Today,we are at the Pajarito domes,it's freezing it's probably 3 degrees right now
我们在拍Walt,Jesse和Saul在沙漠见面的戏份
We are shooting Walt Jesse and Saul in the desert
这个场景里 Walt建议Jesse离开Albuquerque
This is a big scene where Walt comes suggest Jesse to leave Albuquerque
Saul知道一个人 他的专长就是给人新的身份
Saul knows a man,he specializes in giving people new identities
他会帮你搬去很远的地方 为你建立一个新的生活
He would move you some places far away,set you up with a whole new life
我们在很多荒凉的地方拍摄过
There are just so many lonely,desolate places that we shoot
那些地方 有时候是就是角色们感情的缩影
That just are the mere image of how these characters feel at times
就是很孤单 寂寞
It's just so alone and desolate
你就直说要我帮你好了 直说你根本不在乎我的死活
Just ask me for a favor,and tell me you don't give a shit about me
告诉我 不这样做的话你就会杀了我 像你杀死Mike那样
It's either this or you kill me the same way you killed mike
我喜欢演一个跟我自己不一样的人
I feel most comfortable playing someone that I'm not
站在人堆面前 公众讲话会让我很害怕
I got terrified doing public speaking,standing in front of crowds
但是在镜头面前 只要是演跟我完全相反的人
But in front of camera,as long as it's someone completely polar opposite of me
我就会完全放松
That's when I feel most comfortable
不就是这样吗 特地赶到这样荒无人烟的地方
Isn't that what  this is all about  meeting way to hell out here
就是以防我拒绝
Just in case I say no
当你看见Aaron和Bryan一起的时候
When you look at Aaron and Bryan together
你就好像看到那种 良师益友的关系
You can really see the sort of a mentor kind of situation
Aaron在与Bryan相处的时间里成长为一个更好的演员
Where Aaron has only become a better actor for his time spent with Bryan
Bryan Cranston的提升空间就没多少了
There's very little room for improvement with Bryan Cranston
但我认为 在和Aaron一起拍戏时 他意识到自己必须保持最佳状态
But I think he's realized he has to be at the top of his game around Aaron
这种良好的关系是相互的
These two guys are good for one and another
卡 演得太好了
Cut it -cutting -beautiful
为最终集Jack团伙的围场选址
我知道 整部剧将在这个特别的地方结束
I knew the entire series was gonna end at this particular location
把这个地方定好非常的重要
This is a very important location to nail down and get right
我们从编剧们那里知道 我们必须找到这个院子
We knew from the writers that we had to find this compound
它在最终集之前会有亮相
And we are introducing it in an earlier episode
但是这儿将在大结局里扮演非常重要的角色
But that was gonna play a big part in the finale
本来是有点挑战性的
It was little bit challenging
但是因为神的帮助 或者说因为毒师神的帮助
But by the grace of god,or the Breaking Bad gods
我们找到了这个完美的地方
We just ran into this perfect setting
是个老旧的铸模工厂
Which was an old molding plant
这里将上演一场好戏 当我们把一切都弄好了之后
Quite a lot is gonna happen here,by the time we are set and done
如果这是我们最终拍摄的地方的话 我认为是的 非常可能
If this is indeed the place we shoot,and I think it will be,probably
我们想这个桶形建筑
We are thinking this barrel shape building here
很有可能将成为Todd的制毒室
Is probably gonna be Todd's meth lab
这儿两面都有大型的货车门
It's got its giant truck doors on both sides
里面看上去很不错 然后这边的棕色的砖坯房
It looks great inside,and then this brown adobe building
就在我们面前 磨坊前面
Straight ahead of us here in front of the big mill building
很有可能将成为Jack的俱乐部
Is probably gonna be uncle jack's clubhouse
按照我们原先设想的
Originally as conceived
俱乐部 实验室 关押Jesse的地方
The club house,the lab,the place where Jesse contained in
是整个一个大房间
Were all one big room
但是 现在我们看到这么多可以用的建筑
And we've seen now we had all these buildings to play
还有这个吓人的坑
And this fantastic horrifying pit
所以 我和我的团队找到了这个超赞的地方
So my crew and I we found this marvelous location
我和我的编剧们 要把Jesse带到这里
I'm gonna bring Jesse here,my writers and i
我也很确定 最后我们将帮他逃出这里
And I'm pretty sure at the end of all,we're gonna get him out
可以看出 他更担心他 但我不认为除了这样他还能怎样
look you see that,he's more concerned about him but I don't think he can be more this
我明白 -你觉得怎么样
I got you -what do you think
对吧  -对 不错 -即使他像是..对 正是这样
Right -I think it's good -even though he's like..yeah...exactly
今天是特别兴奋的一天 因为今天是Sam Catlin
Today is an incredibly exiting day,because it is sam catlin
我们的编剧兼导演 第一次导演
Our writer and director's,first day directing ever
让他感觉到 我会这么做的
Give him a little something like I'm gonna do it
我想给毒师剧组的人机会
I wanna give people opportunities on Breaking Bad
去成长 学习 尝试新事情
To grow and learn and do new things
这个剧的编剧想要执导 第一个要跨越的障碍就是
Hurdle no.1 to get the job of directing on the show as a writer
必须要有激情 过来问我要执导的机会
Was to have the enthusiasm,require to do it and come to me and ask
我从没有开诚布公地说 他们可以过来找我
I did not make it publicly known that they would come to me
我希望他们是发自内心地想执导
I want them to do it because they really wanted to do it
而不是听说有别的编剧想导演就去跟风
Not because I heard other writers want to do it
是那样吗
Is that it
你想看一眼吗
You wanna take a look
那样行吗
Does that work
你希望一直到结束都保持着紧张是吗
You want me to keep that tension all the way
-是 你明白他会这样做的 会出事的 -从头到尾一直紧张
-yeah you do know he's gonna do it,this is happening -all the way to the end all the way to the end
Aaron 洒点水到这里 我们开始吧
Aaron flashing water on this,let's roll
尽管我对这个想法不是特别有热情
Though I wasn't wild keen on the idea just because
因为我需要他们和我一起待在编剧室里 但我就是不能拒绝他们
I need them in the writers room with me,I just couldn't say no
因为 他们想做 他们值得拥有这个权利 他们也争取到了
Because they wanted it,they deserved it and they earned
有时作为负责人你就是得让他们遵循自己的内心
And sometimes as show runner you just gotta let people follow their hearts
去做他们认为重要的事
And do things that are important to them
我有当导演的各种优势 因为这集剧本是我写的
I had all these advantages coming in because I wrote the episode
我知道这部剧的基调 我也了解这些演员 知道他们的才华所在
I know the tone of the show,and I personally know actors and their talents
于是我可以就着他们的基础来拍
So it was just like I was sort of starting on their base
Jesse 把打火机放下
Jesse put down that lighter
他向一个小孩下毒 一个八岁的男孩
He poisoned a little kid,an 8 year old boy
只是因为 这是一步棋
Just because,you know,just as a move
Walt是个混蛋 我知道了 我们会谈的
Walt's bastard secret's out,we'll talk about it
卡 表演得很棒
Cut,that's beautiful
Sam以前是演员 我知道他会和这些演员合作得很好
Sam used to be an actor,and I knew sam would be great working with the actors
他来到那里的时候很自信 有备而来 知道自己想要的是什么
He came there confident,prepared,knew exactly what he wanted
不会试着画蛇添足
Didn't try to do more than what needed to be done
他的工作完成得很漂亮
And he did a beautiful job
我大学的时候 认识一个年轻人 名叫Takehiko Kitosara
When I was in college,I knew a young man named Takehito Kitosara
CP：Cerebral Palsy 脑瘫
他患有脑瘫
He had CP
挺严重的
He was afflicted with it pretty severely
他需要手杖走路 跟Walt Jr.一样
He needed crutches to walk,as does Walt Jr.
我跟他很熟 他是个很好的人
And I got to know him very well,he was a wonderful person
他属于那种人 你的生命会因为结识他们而变得更加富足
He was one of people you meet in your life that make you richer for having known them
他20多岁就去世了
He passed away in his mid-20s
毕业后没几年
Not too many years after college
我在构思Walt Jr这个角色的时候想到了他
I was thinking of him when I was thinking of Walt Jr
于是就想到了让Walt Jr也患有脑瘫
And the idea of Walt Jr having cp
当他写Walt Jr的时候 他脑子里就想到了他的身体顽疾
When he was writing Walt Jr. He had him in mind his physicality
然后我在剧本上看到他这么写的时候
And what it really was when I saw that on on the script
我就说 哥儿们 写得很精准啊 我能演
I was like,dude,spot on it,I got this
-一切都好吗 -好 只是工作上的事
Everything OK -oh yeah,just work stuff
尽管那个角色患有脑瘫 我们知道我们不想区别对待他
Even though the character has cp,we knew we didn't want to treat him any differently
那个角色不会被区别对待 就像RJ 现实生活中不会被区别对待
The character differently,just like RJ,not treated any differently in real life
如果这有希望能向观众传达一种信息
And that's,hopefully,if that sends a message to the public
就是关于如何与残疾人和谐相处
Of how to integrate with those with apparent disabilities
我认为我们算得上做出了一点贡献
And I think we've done a little to help that up
我爱你伙计 -我也爱你
I love you buddy -I love you too
我是这个星球上最幸运的人 得以和我身旁的这个人一起工作
I'm the luckiest person on this planet to be able to work with this man
我还以为你最想和Bob Odenkirk一起合作呢
I thought it was Bob Odenkirk you really wanted to work with
-别耍我了 别骗我了 -事实上 Bob是...
Don't fool me,don't give me that crap -actually Bob is
你想和Bob合作 不是我
You wanted to work with Bob Odenkirk,not me
我从十三岁就和你一起合作了
I've been working with you since I was 13
-所以说你是烦我咯 -是啊 你得展翅飞翔不是
So you are tired of me -yeah,you know,you got to spread the wings
鸟儿们最终将离开巢穴
The birds have to leave the nest eventually
你就在这里看一眼 然后你就想
If you just take one moment here and you'll just be like
OK 我马上要从最高跳水板上跳下来了 然后就走
OK,I'm gonna jump off the highest diving board and then go
挺酷的 我们很少在《绝命毒师》里拍这么亮堂的景
It's really cool,we've not really done our Breaking Bad in this sort of white color world
原来剧本里写的是要在公园里拍
Originally this was scripted to be sort of a park
而Christian 我们的选址经理 想到了这个点子
Christian our locations manager came up with an idea of this
一个广场 明显不是公园
A plaza which obviously isn't a park
有足够的公开度 很满足我们的需求
With the publicness of it really sort of suits our needs
摄像机对准电话
Camera right to the phone
待在那儿 别动
Hold right there,hold
我们用这个 你看见这个窃听器了吗
We use one of these things,you've seen the earwigs
我把这个放进耳朵里 他耳朵里也有一个
I put this in my ear,he's got one in his ear
我们可以互相听到对方 因为我们还装上了麦
We could hear each other because we are miked also
Aaron在记他的对白
So Aaron is going over his dialogues right now
他在和他的对白挣扎
He's been having the toughest time with his dialogue
看看这个 只有这个 几句对白而已
look at this,it's only this,a little bit of dialogue
但我就是做不到啊
I just can't do it
他以记住准确的台词为荣
He prides himself on getting all these lines exactly right
而我以不记而自豪
And I pride myself on not
他把他的台词藏在电话旁边
He's stuck his lines up on the telephone
-我不会这样做的 -很公平嘛
I'm not gonna do it now -it's all fair,
-不不不 我不会这样做的 -没事啊 白兰度就这么做了
No,no,I'm not gonna do it -do it.hey Brando did it
-我又不是白兰度 -我是指罗伯特白兰度
I'm not Brando though -I meant Bob Brando
我没这么做啊  大家都看到了啊
I didn't do it,just so everyone knows
摄像机在这里 然后你这样看着电话
The camera is here and you are looking at the phone
就把台词藏在那里 不不不 为什么不啊
Just put the lines up on,no no.. Why not
等等等等....
Wait wait wait.....
Allan好了吗
Allan
马上给你接通 就快好了
He's gonna get it for you,he's really there
Bryan在片场的行为都很幼稚
Bryan behaves very immaturely on set
我这样说已经很给他面子了
And I say that in the nicest way possible
卡
Cut it
我这条差点就过了 我勒个去
I almost had it too,damn it,man
我们演的是一个很紧张很黑暗的故事
We are telling a very intense dark story
但是当你没在拍的时候 适当地用幽默来缓和紧张气氛是很好的
When you are not shooting it,it's good to kind of break the tension with humor
他们在谈Bryan的戏份
They are discussing Bryan Cranston's coverage
我的已经拍好了
My coverage is already done
所以今天最重要的部分已经完成了
So really the most important part of the day is finished
但是现在... -我能听见你哦 我有装备 我知道的
But now... -so,I can hear you,I have an accessory,I know
哦 你能听见啊
Oh you can hear me
-麦克风和窃听器啊
-the microphone and the earwig
-哦 我忘了我们还有这个 麦克风和听筒
I forgot that we had this,the mics and earpiece
不过 没关系 他需要听到这些
Well it's good,he needs to hear that you know
我可不想让我的台词掩盖你精湛的演技
Well I don't want my off-camera lines overshadow your on-camera performance
真的 你可以读 Allan也可以读
But really,you could read it or Allan could read it
随便去街上拉一个人过来读也可以
Really get someone off the street to read the line,I don't really..
谁来读 完全没有差别
Really won't make any difference one way or other
大家注意了 开拍了
Here we go guys let's roll
我喜欢我做的事 我觉得很有趣 当人们在这种放松的状态下
I love what I do,I have fun,and when people are at ease
不论是演员们还是工作人员 大家就会更有效率
Whether it's cast or crew,they work better
更开心了嘛  开心了就会表现得更好
They are happier,happier people work better
让你们说我疯了吧 我决定这次拍不看台词
Call me crazy but I'm gonna try this take without looking at my lines
开始了 天哪
Here it goes oh my god
我没预想到《绝命毒师》的片场会这么有趣
I didn't see that Breaking Bad set would be this funny
我都不知道为什么
I really didn't get it
我没想到这儿会变得如此有趣
I didn't know it would gonna be this much fun and this funny a place
这招厉害啊 混蛋
Nice try,asshole
Jesse 你在哪里 我就想跟你谈谈
Jesse where are you,I just wanted to talk to you
不 我不会做你想做的事了 行吗 混蛋
No,I'm not doing anything you want any more,OK,asshole
冷静一下
Just calm down.
我冷静的不得了 给你提个醒 我会抓住你的
I'm super calm,Walt,this is just a heads-up,I'm coming for you
如果我非得指出一个人 那一定是Bryan
If I got to point one person,that of course is Bryan Cranston
Bryan在这一行很久了 他是个专业人士
And Bryan Cranston's been doing this job long enough,he's such a pro
他去过很多片场 好的坏的 他经历过很多情景 好的坏的
He's been on sets,good and bad,he's been in situations,good and bad
我认为 他一路走来做出了很明智的决定
And I think he made a conscious decision along the way
每个人都能尽我们所能的享受其中的乐趣
That everyone is gonna have his as good time as we could have
我们将非常努力地工作
We are all gonna work our butts off
但我们将对彼此非常友善
But we could be kind to each other nice to each other
我们可以成为一个幸福的大家庭
And we can be a happy family
我们一起上 如何
Let's go do this,shall we
不错哟 -进来一起拍
Nice -bring it in,come on in and shot
我们将互撒鲜血了啊 准备好了吗
So we're gonna throw blood on each other,you ready
-你先来 -好的
You do it first -OK
全撒上来啊 向我开炮啊
Get it out,get it all out brother
别顾虑了 6年了 我们
Let it go,six years man
小心哦
Watch out
看上去还可以吗
Does it look OK
我们明天再来拍
..continue the coverage tomorrow
这样阳光能照射到我们
That's gonna put us on the sun-side....
我们在To'Hajilee 这是Walt埋钱的地方
We are in To'Hajilee,this is the place where Walt had buried his money
也是拍Walt被抓的地方
This is the big moment where Walt is actually arrested
在他埋钱的地方
At the spot where his money is
我们应该把主要场景搭在这边 拍车的地方
We should most importantly set it up for our car houses
然后摄像机也要摇过来拍俯瞰镜头
But potentially swing this way and do our down shots this way as well
当我们知道我们第五季第十三集要拍一场枪战
When we knew we are gonna have this shoot-out in episode 513
将导致可怜的Hank的牺牲
That will ultimately lead to poor hank's demise
以及可怜的Gomez的牺牲的时候
And poor Gomez's demise as well
早先我就尽力确保
Very early on I did my best to ensure that
Michelle能执导这非常特别的一集
Michelle Maclaren would get to direct that particular episode
他拿着他的手机和电池
He gets his phone and the battery
找地方藏身
looks for a place to hide
这个场景拍摄量很大 我们有相当多的演员
There was so much to shoot with so many people
剧本里老是提到谁看到谁了 还要组织联系各部人员
And there are so much reference to looks and connecting different groups
于是我想 我们最好先徒步勘察整个场景
And so I thought we'd better walk through the entire,all the scenes
这样大家都能尽快熟悉地形
So that everybody has the geography down
可以了 让他们开拍吧 车停的地方
All right now give them the action the car place
当我看到Gomez出来的时候 对吗
When I see Gomez get out,right
是当你看见Hank的时候 你就表现出 别来别来
It's when you see hank and you are like don't come don't come
-如果我看见Gomez -对 还有Jesse
If I see Gomez.. -you know,Jesse
等等 不不不
Wait a sec..no no no
看你的对白了吗
See your dialogue
什么对白
What's the dialogue
我知道你在那儿 那句
I know you are out here. That one
就这样儿我向你投降呢 开玩笑吧
And I'm giving up to you  you gotta be kidding me
这就是负责把这部剧拍得这么好看的人
This is the man responsible for making this look really good
-他总把我们拍得很好看 -我尽力了
-he always makes us look good,this man right here -I'm trying
多照顾你的摄影师 你的死忠粉摄影师 要么你就死定了
Always take care of your cameraman,your die-hard camera man,dead meat
-我就说这么多 -有些人就是比其他人更难拍得好看啊
-that's all I'm saying -some people are harder to make look good than others
我知道 所以你要更努力啊 有劳了
I know,that's why you have do a harder job,that's why I appreciate it
Andy是我们的A机位摄像
Andy our A camera operator
他和演员之间 有着独特而亲密的关系
Has a very unique and very intimate relationship with our actors
他是相当适合我的摄像师
He's always the guy for me
他会看着你 告诉你镜头效果好不好
Because he's always the guy looking at you and tell you if its a good shot
做这样或那样的调整 所以他是我的第一顾问
looks kind of this or that,so I will go to him first
至少我会先去问他
Or certainly one of the first guys
我们之间不仅步调一致 这样节省了我们很多的时间
It's not only he and I are in harmony in terms of our movements that's saved us a lot of time
拍摄出了很好的效果
Made us look good,you know
而且看上去好像我俩在跳舞一样
And it's almost like you are doing a dance with him
有些时候我们像被绑在了一起
There've been times when literally we've been tied together
我觉得其实我们一直是连在一起的
And I feel like we've been always tied together
Hank 开始查看四周
Hank,so look around
出来吧 Walt！
Come on out,Walt
看见他了
Got him
Walt从没想过Jesse会和Hank合作
Walt never thought that Jesse would be working with hank
Heisenberg好像总是先人一步
Heisenberg always seems to be a step ahead already
把所有的可能性所有的细节都想到了
Think about all the possibilities and all the in-and-outs
但他想都没想过还有这种可能
This didn't even enter his mind
Bryan和我讨论过
Bryan and I discussed
这是Walt至今所经历过的最两难的情形
This is the most in-between moment that that Walt has ever felt up to this point
这是他的穷途末路了 因为唯一的解决方法就是杀了所有人
It's the end of line for him,because the only way out of this is to kill everyone
他准备杀死Jesse
And he was prepared to kill Jesse
但他可没准备杀死Hank
But he's not prepared to kill hank
停下 转身
Stop,turn around
开始时Hank原本是个强势稳定,有把握的人
Hank started out as the together,completely controlled guy
他中途经历了瓦解
And then unraveled
而之后他又重拾了原本的自我
And then hank just now started to come back to where he was before where he was on this game
这就是他揭穿Walt的时候
and that's where he gets Walt
因为他终于夺回游戏主动权 类似走了一个大圆圈
Because he finally gets back to this game,you know,it's kind of a full circle
跪下来
Get on your knees
这是Hank的胜利时刻
This is hank's moment of victory
我觉得他从这得到了一种成就感
I think there is a sense of accomplishment for this
想想看 为了这一刻 这个人牺牲了自己的工作
Because you know we finally at that moment,this guy's sacrificed his job
自己的婚姻 他倾其所有去抓这个毒枭
His marriage,I mean,everything he took to bust this guy doing meth
爱死他了
I love him..
Steven 好像是我第一天进剧组就认识他了
Steven,we met maybe the very first day that I went on
在那个片场 我们见了Vince 还见了缉毒署的顾问
It was on set where we met Vince,and we met our DEA adviser
然后我们就一见钟情了
And we just hit it off
缉毒署训练你们干嘛了
How did you guys see,with the DEA training
我们抓了一些嗑药的
We busted some fucking crackheads
是啊 我记得
Yeah,I remember that
那你们是一起出任务了吗
Did you say you did a ride-along
没 没出任务 他们不让
No.we didn't do a ride-along they wouldn't let us
我们自己微服出巡 抓了几个瘾君子
But we just went out and busted some crackheads,on our own
在拍剧的第一天就结识了我最好的朋友真的是很棒
It was good to meet my best friend on the show,on the first day
我们得是搭档嘛
You know,we have to be partners
和这个人在片场很开心
Just being on set with this guy is exciting
我喜欢他和大伙相处的方式
Because I like the way the treats everybody around him
我正在跟他学怎么接人待物 这是我俩一起学习的另外一课
I'm learning how to do that,it's another lesson I'm taking with him
能描述一下吗
How would you define that
这么说吧 很简单
Well it's truly easy
在派对上打招呼要这样说 最近咋样啊 小娘炮
In a party you just go,what's up you pussies
你刚到 看看我们几点到
You just got here,fucking the way like we do
6点 你这个小娘炮
6AM you fucking pussy
他这是在说早上好
Good morning from Dean Dorris
Norris先生 你在哈佛上学的时候也是这么说话的吗
Mr.Norris,is that the way you spoke when you were at Harvard university
你真是这样说话的吗
Is that the way you really spoke
他是我见过的最不像从哈佛毕业的哈佛毕业生
He's most unlikely Harvard grad I've ever met in my life
拿到全奖的哈佛毕业生噢
Full-ride Harvard university graduate
我都不知道你在想些啥屁东西 小贱人Mark
I don't even know what the fuck you are thinking,mark bitch
他是在说 谢谢我没事
That means thanks,I'm fine
我总觉得我在片场的时候得表演点什么
I always feel like I have to do a little show when I'm on the set
因为这样我能自在些
Because it made me feel more comfortable
我想跟大家套近乎
Because I want people to be on my side
这样我们做正经事的时候
So that when we have to do serious stuff
我会觉得大家都站我这边
I feel like they are on my side
所以我来片场的时候经常做些搞笑举动
So I always feel like I come to set and do a little tap dance
以我自己粗犷的方式博大家一笑
Try to make people laugh and in my own bolder way
-挺不容易 -像我一样 说那么多草泥马
-it's hard,-it's hard to say motherfuckers as much as I do
还不冒犯到别人 挺不容易
Without people getting offended
实际上 他们现在挺喜欢我说草泥马的
Actually,they like it when I say motherfucker now
好多人没在干活儿啊
A lot of guys standing around doing nothing
有没有搞错 草泥马的
Wait a minute,motherfuckers
看 没在干活 没在干活 没在干活
look,nothing,nothing,nothing..
你们今天都是来混的啊 啥都不做
You are all doing teamster work today,nothing
你知道上帝对这些混饭吃的人怎么说的吗
You know what Jesus said to teamsters right
在我回来之前你们什么都不用做
Don't do anything till I get back
从我们现有的开始
So it starts off exactly what we have
场景在一个吸尘器店展开
It starts off when we are in the vacuum cleaner shop
我们会看到一个售货员 他正在招呼一位女士
We are meeting this guy,who is waiting on a lady
他卖吸尘器卖得不错......诶 我们跑的太偏了吧
He's a really good vacuum cleaner guy,where the hell are we ..
当我们在To'Hajilee拍这场枪战的时候
So when we were out in To'Hajilee doing the shoot out
Vince在Albuquerque为第五季第十六集做准备
Vince was in Albuquerque because he was prepping for 516
但他们还在修改编写第十五集
But they were still breaking and writing 515
那个设定有问题
That setting gets a problem
Saul和Walt之间的关系 以及办身份证的人和Walt之间的关系
That thing with Saul and Walt and the thing with the Disappearer and Walt
他们感觉好像就是
They kinda feel like we are working a group...
我们用尽策略想让他们有不同的感觉
We are tap dancing really hard to make sure that they feel different
结果他们还是有相似的感觉
But.. They kind of have a similar feel
我们把《绝命毒师》最后几集引向了苦涩的结局
We wrote the last couple of episodes of Breaking Bad right up to the bitter end
我们六个编剧一度减少到了两个
My six writers got dwindled down to at one point two writers
Peter和Tom
Peter Gould and tom Schnauze
我们在Albuquerque的特设工作室工作
And we worked in an ad hoc office in Albuquerque and
我们尽力使故事顺畅进行
We did our best to keep the story flowing
当创作的人少了 就挺困难的
It's tough in those moments when you don't have many brains in the room
然后你的工作环境你也不熟悉
And you have a weird room you are not familiar with
你就得尽力克服这些障碍 完成好工作
You just make dos as best as you can
我们就把他们聚结在一起  让他们在同一个场景出现怎么样
What if we just conglomerate them,just kinda squeeze them together into one scene
把这做成引子 很长的引子
And make it into a teaser,a god damn long teaser
我最初的想法是导演最后两集
My initial thought was to direct the final 2 episodes of Breaking Bad
第十五集和第十六集
To direct 515 and 516
但是后来最后八集一开机的时候我就认识到
But it became pretty clear to me early on on the breaking of this final 8 episodes
我没那么多时间
That I wouldn't have the time
但我很开心我最后做到了
And I'm really glad that I did them ultimately
因为最后一阶段我们有Rian加入进来导演
Because it allowed us to fit Rian Johnson in as a director for one more go-round
开始彩排了 开始了 Michael
Comes the rehearsal guys,here we go,action Michael
第五季 第十四集 《奥西曼提斯》
导演:Rian Johnson 编剧:Moira Walley-Beckett
这是Rian跟我们合作的第三集
This is Rian's third episode with us
令人印象深刻的《苍蝇》那集就是他的作品
He did the memorable fly episode
那可能也是我们比较有争议的一集了
Maybe one of our more controversial episodes
去年 他还导了Skyler走进泳池的那集
Last year,he did the episode where Skyler walks into the pool and
他是个非常出色的导演 他也把他的优秀带进了我们剧组
He's a terrific director and he's bringing that same kind of pro to this
今天的这场戏 实际上是一整幕的戏
Today's scene,which is the entire act in fact
非常壮烈的场面 因为我们将失去两位角色
Is so huge because we are losing two of our characters
马上要开拍了 Gomez已经在枪战过后躺在地上牺牲了
The scene is gonna open and Gomez is already dead on the ground after the shoot-out
Hank已经受重伤但并不致命 但他今天还是会死
And hank is severely wounded but not mortally,and he is gonna die today
卡 漂亮 看看呐
Cut it,beautiful,check that,check it in
其实有点怪  你知道 就要死了就要死了
It was kind of weird that,you know the idea,it's coming and it's coming
然后死期到了 过程很难熬
And then there you are,it was trying time
我的意思是 在那拍摄很辛苦
I mean,it was tough shooting out there
如果在你很努力表演的时候 沙子不断飘进你眼睛里
If you are trying to do a scene and the sand is getting in your eyes
这不是拍摄的好地方 这样的态度也不行
It was not great circumstances to shoot,so that kind of attitude too
很长一段时间以来 Dean的角色是黑白分明的
For a long time,Dean's character things were black and white
他成了道德中心
And he became sort of the moral center
他在办的这整个Heisenberg案子
This whole Heisenberg chase that he has been on
真的测试出了他的本性
Has really tested what he's made of
但是Hank最终选择了正义的一方
But hank ultimately chooses what is right
我的名字是助理特工主管Schrader  你他妈的去死吧
My name is ASAC schrader and you can fuck yourself
Hank 你得配合我 好吗
Hank,you got to work with me here OK
Hank一开始就知道完了
Hank knows from the beginning that it's over
但是Walt还在哀求他们放过Hank
And Walt is still trying to beg them to not shoot hank,to kill him
但是Hank知道这于事无补
But hank knew it wouldn't matter,you know
你是我见过最聪明的人
You are the smartest man I've ever met
但你却不知道他十分钟之前就做好决定了
But you can't see that he made up his mind 10 minutes ago
当你直视Dean的眼睛的时候 你能看到他给Hank带来的特质
You look into Dean's eyes and you are seeing what he's bringing to it
你能看见他内在的力量
You can see this inner strength there
这几乎是整部剧里Hank这个角色的核心
That's kind of has been the heart of hank throughout the whole series
你可以看到他最后一刻的镇定从容
And seeing that poise through the final moments
对 这就是最适合他的 壮烈的谢幕方式
Yeah,that's the way you go out
拍得很漂亮 恰到好处 尽管情节很悲伤 但能感到正义
It's beautiful,and it feels right,and as sad as it is,if feels just
与《X档案》的某些正义元素类似
And it feels like the right kind of X-File character
明天见 兄弟
See you tomorrow,bro
谢天谢地终于走了 麻烦蛋一个
Thank god he's gone some pain in the ass he is,oh my god
我绝不会在他面前说他坏话的
I would never,you know,say it in front of him
不过我挺乐意拍下来
And I certainly want this recorded
神呐 生活突然变美好了
God,our lives all just got a little better right now
你说呢
What do you think
坦诚点 真的 开口吧
Just be yourself,that's all,just ask,man
-你知我知 -有人摄像
It's a safe conversation -what about the camera..
啊哦 这什么时候冒出来的
Wow,when do that appear
Hank被杀的情节 实际拍了两天
Killing hank actually happened two days
第一天他被杀
He was shot on one day
而在第二天他的尸体被人拖走 扔到一个洞里
And then the next his body was dragged and dropped in the hole
就是这家伙 让我马上就能头部中弹了
He's the guy,bullet in the fucking head right now
那个妆看起来像个粉刺
looks like a pimple right now
助理特工主管Hank Schrader 外号小粉刺
The pimple the A Hank Schrader
锁定二台记得看我 混蛋们
Catch me on channel 2 motherfuckers
好的好的 开始拍了
OK,here we go here we go,walk away
喊开拍后 你们拖着他走
You guys are dragging him on action
开拍
Action
停
Cut it
继续拖啊 伙计们
Keep dragging him guys,keep going
各位 万众瞩目的一刻来了
Alright guys,it's the moment everyone's been waiting for
整整60集之后
60 episodes later
Dean Norris谢幕
Dean Norris
去CBS拍《穹顶之下》
你要去CBS了
You are going on to CBS
百万观众都能看你笑话了
Where millions and millions more people will see through your inadequacy
祝你们一切顺利
We wish you all the best to and everybody else
谢谢 我们会想你的
Thank you man.that's.. -we're gonna miss you
谢了 伙计 -很开心
Appreciate it thank you guys -it's been a pleasure...
这是嘛玩意啊
What the fuck is this
你也有
And you too
谢谢你们 谢谢
Thank you guys,thanks a lot
如果你在我们拍首播集的时候告诉我
If you told me back in the first day of shooting,the pilot episode
大结局的时候我会多难过
How sad I was gonna be at the end of all
眼看Hank这个角色离开
To see the character Hank Schrader go
我觉得我会很惊讶
I think it would have surprised me because
我并没将Hank预想成一个多么有趣的角色
I didn't foresee the character being all that interesting
我想他就是那种 热情友好的男子汉
I thought of him as kind of an hail-fellow-well-met
耀武扬威的家伙 和Walt完全不一样
Macho swaggering guy who is everything that Walter White was not
然后我们选中了Dean来演这个角色 而Dean要比那丰富得多
Then we cast Dean Norris,and Dean is so much more than that
他是个复杂的人 很出色 很多面的人
He is a complicated man and a wonderful man who has a lot of layers
我无法想象这部剧没了Dean会变成什么样
And I can't imagine what the show would have been without Dean Norris playing hank
你能感觉到就快大结局了
You feel closures happening
每次我们拍完一集 就感觉会有扇门被关上
Little doors,each time we get to another stop little doors are closing
天呐 哥们儿
Oh my god,yeah.brother
越来越难过 越来越悲伤了
It's getting nastier and sadder,you know
非常正确 Anna你准备好了吗
That's correct,anna are you ready
预备 3 2 1 开拍
Here we go,rolling and 3,2,1,action
不 求你了... Walt
No,please.....Walt
干得漂亮
Beautifully done
那场戏是六年来我这个角色的高潮
That scene was the culmination for me of 6 years of the show
我知道这场戏会有多难拍 多有挑战性
I knew how difficult that was gonna be,how challenging it was gonna be
所以他们特地为我准备了个小房间
So they had a little bedroom for me and
我走进去一直待在那里
I went in there and I just kept myself in that zone
然后他们走进来说 对不起 我们得等一段时间 下雪了
And then they came in and said sorry,we gotta hold,it's snowing
我就不得不在那里坐了一整天
I had to kind of sit on it the whole day
然后他们再进来跟我说 雪停了 可以继续了
Then they came back and said OK,it stopped snowing,we were ready to go now
求你停下来  求你了 求你了
Please stop,please,please...
有时候对于一个演员 会有这种情况
Sometimes what happens is an actor,is you get to the moment
当需要你投身进去的时候 你的身体说不行
When it's time to give it over,and your body says I don't want to
因为陷进去很可怕
Because it's scary
在我前几条NG后 Rian到我身边来
Rian came up to me after the first few passes
对我说 听着 你不必担心跌倒在街上
And said to me listen,you don't have to worry about falling down to the street
我说我只是害怕
And I said I am just scared
他就说 我能理解 没事的
And he said,yeah,OK,OK
他知道 我需要有人真心地牵着我的手
He just knew that I needed somebody to essentially take my hand
真诚地说 你很安全
In essence to say,you are safe
准备拍了
Roll it
他看着我
And he looked at me and he saw it
他说 行了 他就默默地转过身 说 开拍吧
And he said OK,and he turned around quietly and said let's go
他走开了 我们继续拍 然后我们做到了
And he walked away,and there we were,and then we did it
求你了
Please,please....
感觉很真实
It feels so real
因为Anna把自己当成了Skyler 经历着情感上的跌宕起伏
Because anna put herself in Skyler's shoes on that emotional roller-coaster
我想对得起那么漂亮的剧本
I want to honor that beautiful piece of writing
我想把这个角色塑造得很好
And I want to honor that character
尽我所能地演好
By giving it everything I know I have to give it
后来我谢谢他帮了我
Afterwards when I thanked him for helping me
他说 我和这可没关系 是你的功劳
He said,well,I didn't have anything to do,I mean,you did it all
但是 是他帮助我做到的
But you know,he helped make it happen
有时候我起床投几个篮
Sometimes I get up and just kind of shoot a basket
得到灵感 然后再休息
And get inspiration and take a break
《绝命毒师》其实有两个中心
For Breaking Bad there's really two centers of the show
一个是Albuquerque的制作中心
There's the production center in Albuquerque
那是我们的演员和工作人员主要待的地方
Where our cast and crews spend most of their time
然后还有我们的后期与编剧中心 在加州的Burbank
And then there's our post-production and our writing center here Burbank California
听着 反基督徒先生 我不会让你把这件事搞砸的
look,Mr. Natural,I'm not gonna let you sabotage this thing
如果你磕飞了去找他 他是不会带你走的
This guy is not gonna take you if you show up high
别闹了 这关乎我俩的性命
So stop screwing around,or it's both our asses
基本上 你制作一部电视剧要走三遍
Basically you make an episode of TV 3 times
首先你写好剧本 然后拍摄 最后剪辑
First you write it,you shoot it,and you edit it
你需要把故事说三遍
You got to tell the story 3 times
所以33%的《绝命毒师》
A big 33% of the story telling in Breaking Bad happened
是在McDonald和Dixon的剪辑室里完成的
In those editing rooms of McDonald and Dixon
这些我都喜欢 我们超时多少了
I love all those stuff,how much over are we
144秒 我坚持保留这段的唯一原因是
144s,the only reason I'm insisting this
因为这是唯一一次的
Is because this is the only time
他把大麻放进了口袋里的场景
That he's got this weed,and he's putting it in his pocket
我是认真的掐灭了 这是A机位的画面
I mean it,put it out,that's the a-side
B机位画面是 听着反基督徒先生
B-side is look,Mr.natural
所以你要剪掉的是
So you are cutting out
你是不是情绪崩溃了
I'm starting to think you've had some kind of mental break here
我认为Vince有独特的节奏感
I think Vince does have unique sense of rhythm
很多时候他工作时会看剪下来的片段
A lot of time he'll look at cuts when he's working
他会说你能再放一遍吗 你能再放一遍吗
And he'll say can you play that again,can you play that again
我需要找到节奏感
I'm really trying to get a sense of the rhythm here
当Jesse意识到Saul让Huell偷走了他口袋里的大麻
When Jesse realized that Saul had Huell lift the marijuana out of his pocket
导演决定用环形视角围绕Jesse来拍
The director decided at that moment to run a circle around Jesse
于是我们得到的片段就是这样的环绕视角
So we've got footage of a camera going around Jesse
也就是Jesse拍口袋的动作
But we've also got Jesse patting himself down
我们决定 与其只使用一个摄像机的一个连续镜头
And what we decided to do,instead of just having it be one camera move you know,one shot
不如把这个镜头分拆几段
I decided to cut the shot up
这样 我就能营造一点紧张的气氛
In that way,I can create a little bit of tension,a little bit of nervousness
实际上更有复杂的镜头效果
Actually makes for a more confusing shot
好的 你觉得那是几点
OK,it's um..what time would you think it is
-清晨 -清晨 那就是差不多5点 早上5点半
Early morning. -early morning,so it's like 5 in the morning,5:30 in the morning
周围很安静 没有车辆往来
It's quiet,ambiance-wise,you know,no cars
音效定点会议是在图像定下来后进行的
The spotting session is finally when the picture is locked
我们每个画面看下来 讨论还有什么要添加的
And we go scene to scene and discuss what is needed to complete the process
这是录下来的引擎的声音吗 -不是的 这是用Vatic软件做的
Is this production of the engine -no this is the VATIC
那做得很好啊
That's pretty good though,it's pretty good
我们的音效定点会议 Vince总是在场的
In our spotting session,we always had Vince of course
Michelle也经常在
Michelle Maclaren will often be there as well
还有我们的监制和音响编辑师Nick
And then we have our supervisor and sound editor,nick
我们的配音师Kathryn
Our ADR supervisor Kathryn Madison
我们的配乐Dave 音乐监制Thomas
Our composer Dave porter,our music supervisor Thomas
还有我们的音乐编辑 Jason
Our music editor,Jason Numan
我在那里 那集的剪辑师也在那里
I'm there and also the editor of the episode is there
我们讨论哪里应该配乐 哪里不应该
And we discuss where music should be added or not added
我们想要的音响效果是怎样的
What we wanted the sound effect to be
我们想要的背景是怎样的
What kind of backgrounds we want
需不需要清理掉一些对白
If there was any dialogue that needs to be cleaned up
现在关于那个吱吱声只有一点问题
The only thing about the squeak now
就是我看着那个东西 感觉好像
That I'm looking at the thing it feels almost
那个听起来 好像秋千发出的声音
It almost sounds like a swing set
磕嗨了荡秋千的感觉
A little swing set versus marijuana
低音部分我觉得还不错 但是中间部分
I like the low end of it,it feels like it's at middle
我可以加进一些更刺耳的咯吱声
But I can add more little higher squeaks
感觉好像是中间的轴承 不拉不拉地转动
Feels like in the middle it's like a bearing...blah-blah
你知道吗就像 我听到什么了吗 那是什么声音
You know like,did I hear something  what's that
还有就是他的鞋跟
And then his heels
他不是一直那样做 但时不时地会把鞋跟拖在地上
He doesn't always do it but a little bit fold his heels dragged on the ground
我刚发现 你可以看见看地上划出的线条
Actually I realized you can see,look at the line in the ground
他的鞋跟划出来的
That his heels has left
我从没注意过
I never noticed it
Porter先生 你有什么想法 音乐方面的
Mr.Porter,What do you think,music-wise
我不确定这儿应该配什么音乐
I'm not sure what score would be adding here
除非你要给这个场景加入一些想法 超现实主义元素的
Unless you had a thought that you wanted to add to the scene,in terms of its surreal-ness
Dave有这样一种优秀的见解
Dave is really wonderful about kind of understanding
他知道故事占据首要地位 音乐是辅助
The story is first,and the music serves the story
对我来说 那段的音乐应该是很柔和 静谧 还带有清晨的丝丝凉意
For me,it plays pretty nicely,quiet and cold in the morning
是的 我觉得你说的很对 如果你问我
Yeah,I think you are right,if you ask me the question
我希望配音带有什么样的感情 我不能直接告诉你
What emotion would I want music to add I couldn't really tell you
因为整个情况 就是带着点安静和神秘感
Because the whole thing is kind of quiet and mysterious also
转盘的静止
The stillness of the merry-go-round
Jesse的脚拖着地
Jesse's foot is kind of dragged on the ground
那种声音的空洞 向你展示了那瞬间所包含的所有内容
And the spareness of that sound tells you everything you need to know at that moment
在最后 如果你突然看到结局 会有种刺痛的感觉
And at the end if you suddenly came at the end that'd be a sting
还有什么好说的
What would be saying anyway or so
《绝命毒师》的后期绝对是这部剧艺术价值的核心
The post-process for Breaking Bad is absolutely a center for artistry
这部剧从各个角度整个被提升了
The show is elevated in every way she's been formed
《绝命毒师》的诞生其实是在后期阶段
The show becomes Breaking Bad in post
不错
It's good
我觉得Saul那种想成为纨绔子弟的人
I think Saul is a guy who wants to be a bit of a play boy
钱 房 权 要啥有啥 所以他会把头发往后梳
Money house powers,so he's got half the hair in back
还要把头发往上梳
And he's got half the hair on top
Donald Trump：地产大亨
你要是有一头Donald Trumps那样的头发
look,when you got hair like Donald Trumps
在这个大千世界 任何东西都是手到擒来
Out in the world,you know,anything goes
嘿 Bryan 最近怎么样啊
Hey,Bryan,how are doing buddy
-唉 就这样了 -对啊 就结束了
This is it,huh -this is it
-不敢相信 -难以置信 是吗
-I can't believe it. -hard to believe,right
但是 这是一场很棒的戏 我很喜欢
But you know,it's a great scene,I love it
这是Bob在《绝命毒师》的最后一个场景了
This is Bob Odenkirk's last scene on Breaking Bad
对我个人来说 这是件大事
For me personally,it's a big deal
Bob 我很幸运能在第二季的时候请到他来演这个角色
Bob,I was lucky enough to introduce him back in season 2
所以开始拍第一场Saul的戏的时候 我就在场
So I was on set when we first started creating the character Saul Goodman
那时我们拍了第一个电视广告
And we shot the very first TV commercial
我跟Bob真的是合作得很开心
And I just got a lot really great time with Saul Goodman,with Bob Odenkirk
我很难过这一切都要结束了
End I'm very sorry it's coming to an end
他们会赶走你的妻儿
They will RICO your wife and kids out of the house
房子没了 你的银行账户被冻结了
That condo is gone,you banks accounts are frozen
你的妻子的照片现在可能已经登上新闻了
You wife's picture is probably on the news right now
就在你的照片的旁边 谁还会雇用她
Right next yours,who's gonna hire her
Vince制作节目的特点是
The thing that Vince does in the show
他不会避开行为的后果不谈
He doesn't avoid the consequences of this behavior
几乎其他的电影啊电视节目啊都会避开后果 为了好玩
Almost any other movie or TV show skirt the consequences just for fun
你以为我想逃
You think I wanted to run
你以为我想像这样抛下她 这是我最不想做的事了
You think I wanted to leave her like this  it's the last thing that I want
在任何剧里 一个硬汉警官
It's a tough detective on an episode of any given drama
枪杀了某个人 然后下一集
Shoot somebody dead and then the next episode
竟然好像什么事都没发生过一样
It's as if this never happened
我不认为现实生活中会是这样
I don't think real life work that way
所以我觉得很重要的是 我们对现实生活的再现
So it's important to me,on this tiny little reenactment of life
也就是指《绝命毒师》我希望它可以更符合现实
That we call Breaking Bad,to mirror reality a little more accurately
我要杀了Jack和他的帮凶
I'm gonna kill jack and his entire crew
我要拿回属于我的东西再转交给我的孩子
I'm gonna take back what is mine and give it to my children
到那时 只有到那时 我才会放手
And then,and only then,will I be through
我们既有精湛的制作水平
With incredibly film making
又有相当黑暗 以至于让人甚至感到有点性感的剧情
and a kind of somewhat sexy kind of scenario that's crazy dark you know
Vince在挑逗观众看这部剧
Vince's tricking people into watching a show
看人们是如何做出错误决定的
And a story about people making bad choices
以及随之而来的后果又是什么
And the consequences that come
这件事不算完直到.....-都结束了
It's not over until i....-it's over
这就是Bob在这部剧里的收尾
That is a series wrap on Bob Odenkirk
非常感谢大家 谢谢
Thank you so much,thank you
好吧 虽然我已经说过很多遍了 但我还是要说
Well,I've said it too many times but I'm gonna keep saying it
参与拍这部戏是上天赐给我的礼物
Being here has been an incredible gift to me
在每一方面都是 很难仔细解释给你们听
In every way,it's hard to tell you
因为实在是一言难尽
Because I have to tell you a long story
所以 谢谢  感谢你们的专业 你们的敬业
So thank you,than you for your professionalism your quality
感谢你们的丰富的经验和美好的人格
Your great great experience and personalities
还有你们的热情欢迎 这个角色是我一生的财富
And being so welcoming and this part has been a gift to me
我怎么感谢你们都不够
I'll never,you know be able to thank anyone enough
准备就绪 Robert开拍
Here we go we're set,and action Robert
我认为关于倒数第二集 一个有趣的事情是
I think a really interesting thing about our penultimate episode
大家通常会认为我们做好剧情收尾工作就行了
Is one would expect that we would just be wrapping things up
然而我们却引入了一个新的角色
And instead we are actually introducing a new character
而且我们还为新角色搭建了全新的布景
And we were introducing it in an entirely new setting
兰伯特先生 欢迎来到新罕布什尔州
Mr.Lambert,welcome to New Hampshire
我们正处在森蒂亚峰顶
We are at top of the Sandia Crest
第一批西班牙探险者给它命的名
The original Spanish explorers named that
因为一到晚上 这座山就会沐浴在橙红的夕阳之中
Cuz' in the evening this mountain are lit up in beautiful red orange
看起来像一片西瓜 Sandia在西语中就是西瓜的意思 所以这样叫
They look like a big slice of watermelon,that's why it's called sandía
我们正处在山顶
We're at top of them right now
这座山俯瞰Albuquerque城
And they overlook Albuquerque
所以直线距离上 我们其实没走那么远
So we are not that far as a crow-fly
这离我们的摄影棚也不远
That far away from our sound stages
对我来说 这就好像是在拍David Lean或者Stanley Kubrick的片子一样
To me,this is like me getting to play David Lean or Stanley Kubrick
因为我们建造了这样的布景
Because of something we've got to build
我们要在现场拍摄小屋的外景
Exterior of this cabin on location
而内景则在舞台拍摄
And we have the interior on stage
小屋不仅仅像《闪灵》中的山顶酒店
Not only like the Overlook Hotel
光是看上去就很棒
I think it's looking just fantastic
我根本没法在你们觉得正好的时机把门关上
But I will never be able to close the door,that would be,at timing you enjoy
我们来看看是什么问题 -好
Let's see what happens -alright
我喜欢硬汉角色 传统的老式的纯正硬汉角色
I love tough guys,good old-fashioned old-school tough guys
他们不是那种炫耀卖弄的人 而是安静的人
Not guys who poster and flex,but guys who are quiet
Mike就是这种硬汉
Mike Ehmantraut is one of the tough guys
Robert Forster同样也是这种硬汉的代表
And Robert Forster represents another one of those tough guys.
一个月以后见
See you in a month
每一次接到新对白 演员们都是从零开始的
The actor starts at zero with every new piece of dialogue.
他需要在短短的拍摄时间内 从零分达到十分
He is trying to get to ten by the time he finishing shooting
而且每次都必须走一遍从零到十的过程
You got to go from 0 to 10 for every single time
先前的工作经验并不会带来什么优势
There's no advantage to having worked before
你得以新材料为起点 认真学习它
You got to start it with new material and learn it and fan it out
把它理解透彻 并且全力投入地表演
And understand it and try to mean it
你为这花了大钱
You paid good money for this
在这你有两英亩的地盘 很多树 还有个暖和的地方住
You got two acres up here. Lots of woods,a nice warm place
我觉得这儿正是一个能让人休息思索的好地方
Seems to me just the spot for a man to rest up,think on things
四处看看的话 风景不错
If you look around,it's beautiful
你帮了大忙 谢谢你
You've been very helpful. Thank you.
一个月以后见
See you in a month
编剧室走过六个年头了 -对啊
It's been 6 years in this room -yeah it has been
2007年就开始了 -真难以相信啊
2007 -hard to believe,can't
那会儿还是艾森豪威尔当政吧
Eisenhower was president
这是我们最后的剧情卡片了 第五季第十六集的
These are our last couple of cards of E516
也就是全剧第六十二集《绝命毒师》的最后一集
Which is the episode 62,which is the very last episode ever for the Breaking Bad
能把这些卡片贴上去么 -好的
You wanna start putting some of those up -yep
最后一次拜访....他挚爱的实验室..
.....meth lab,last visit,to his precious.....
好的 要贴最后一张了 要贴最后一张了
OK,last card,last card,alright
不要啊 不要啊
Don't do it don't do it
每一季完结后 我们都会庆祝
We celebrate every time we end a season on Breaking Bad
特别是喜欢用香槟来庆祝
We typically celebrate with champagne
在编剧室挂上最后一张卡片
In the writers room we put up the last card
感觉像是非常隆重的一刻
And it feels like a very momentous occasion
我们有个小小的传统 我们会把标有集数的卡片挂起来
We have a little tradition we put up the number of the episode
这张正好是第五季第十六集的 马上就挂它了
This one happens to be 516 and we put it up
最后一件事 就是把它挂在这个角落 嗯... 好了
So last thing we do,we put it up on the corner here...and...bingo
结束了《绝命毒师》编剧室的工作到此结束
This is the end,this is the end of the Breaking Bad writer's room right here
这一次的结束 比以往任何一次都伤感
This time was sadder than other times in the past
因为我们知道这会是最后一次了
Because we knew for sure it's the last time
我以为我感到的是悲伤
You know I think I feel sad about it
实际上我感到的却是有点麻木了 真是吓一跳
Instead I just feel kind of numb,I was a bit in shock
而且 到现在几个月的时间了 我还没去消化这件事
And I still haven't processed it many months later now
给最后几集做剪辑的时候
As we edited the final episodes
我也没意识到它已经完结了
It still hasn't a completely dawned on me that it's over
那可是标志结束的重大时刻 最后一张卡片被挂上去的时候
That was a big moment of ending that last card going up
工作里面最难的部分 就是往后写剧情
That's the hardest part of the job breaking the episodes
当最后一片剧情卡被挂上去的时候
When that last one goes up
你就真正认识到 自己终于要停产了
You really know you finally are out of childbirth
敬我们最棒的编剧 最棒的演员
A toast to the best writers,best actors
最棒的制片 以及最棒的所有的工作人员 你们永远是最棒的
Best producers,best crew on TV ever now and forever
感谢所有人 你们的努力成就了这部剧
Thank you for all you guys for making the show what it's been.
上帝保佑你们 -干杯
God bless you. -cheers.
现在是2013年3月10号 我和Aaron在我的Albuquerque居所
It's march 10th,2013 We are at my house in Albuquerque
我们正准备读《绝命毒师》最后一集的剧本
He's Aaron,I'm Bryan we are reading the last episode of Breaking Bad
我们还没看过..是的 我们不知道会怎样
We haven't read it yet....we don't know
我们正喝啤酒呢
And we are having beer
我真是超级郁闷 该来的终于要来了
I am so unbelievably depressed that this is happening right now
我知道你们都懂的
I know you all understand.
这对我来说真的是很私人化的经历 大约每隔一周拿到剧本
It was such a personal experience to get the scripts every other week,about
你私下读着它们
And you privately read them and
你会受到剧情的冲击并产生个人情感
Have your own personal sensation of..an impact of it.
既然这是最后一季了
And since this was going to the very last season
我想 我们也许可以在镜头前 朗读这段最后的剧本
I thought what if we read the very last script cold on camera
这就是结束了
This is it..
开车去他家 泊车 进了门 喝杯啤酒
Just going in there,picking up a beer,driving there and parking...
我害怕临近结束的每分每秒
I was dreading every moment of it
砰砰砰...整间屋子爆发着机枪的怒吼
Bah bah bah...the entire room erupts in machine gunfire
闪着红光的枪弹穿透墙壁
Red tazers ripped through the walls
就像是《星际迷航》里的相位枪发出来的
Like Phaser beams right out of star trek
弹雨撂倒了Jack及其同伙
Cutting through jack's gang
好似滚烫的刀锋划入一块黄油那般利索
Like hot knifes through butter
那架巨大的M-60机枪先前被摆在小道上
That big M-60 has been placed in their sideways
安置在那个Walt组装的装置的顶上
Mounted at the the top of the rig Walt built
它咯吱发响 前后来回扫动
It rattles away,sweeping back and forth
就像是撒旦的雨刷器一样
Like Satan's windshield wiper
大家准备好吧 这个注定要发生的
Prepare yourselves people,cuz' it is happening
说出来 说这是你想要的
Say the words,say you want this
你不开口 那什么都不会发生
Nothing happens until I hear you say it
这是我想要的
I want this.
Jesse思考片刻 哗啦一声把枪丢在了地上
Jesse figured as much,he let the gun clatter to the floor
那你就自己动手吧
Then do it yourself
说完这句 他便转身离开了
With that,he turns and walks out
他和Jesse最后相视良久
He and Jesse share one last long look
Jesse挂上档 开动了车
Then Jesse chunks the car into gear and hunches it
这辆雪佛兰埃尔卡米诺嗥叫着 冲向夜色
The El Camino go squealing away into the night
Walt站在那里看他离开
Walt stands there watching him go
Jesse加足马力冲向铁链紧缩的大门
Jesse speeds up towards the chain-link locked gate
梆...他冲出大门 好像那根本不算什么
Bang,he smashes through it like it was nothing
我们的镜头离开围场 给Jesse一个特写
We leave the compound behind,close angle on Jesse
他的表情坚毅而无畏 加速奔向黑暗中去
Grimly-determined,fearing nothing,he speeds towards the darkness
接下来就由我们去想 他将去向何处
It's up to us to say where he's headed
他会有更好的归宿 我能说的就这么多
I'd like to call it something better,I leave it at that
俯视 我们从空中往下看到了Walt
Bird's eye view: We look straight down on Walt
他这时跌倒到地板上 然后平躺着
As he tumbles into frame,lying flat on his back on the floor.
他的眼睛望向我们 毫无生机
His eyes staring up at us,lifeless.
然而 他最后的表情却又流露出那么一丝心满意足
And yet,his final expression is one of faint satisfaction
我们依旧保持俯瞰视角 向下看着他
We continue skyward,looking down on Walt
镜头保持上升 再上升
Rising as high as we can go
慢慢地 从这个画面渐变到一片漆黑
Off this image,slowly fading to black...
全剧终
End of series
哇哦
Wow..
我觉得不会有续集了
So I guess there won't be a sequel
但是Jesse活下来了
But Jesse stays alive.
你感觉怎样
How do you feel
哦 我有点伤感 很棒 真的 你懂的
Oh man,I feel sad..it's great I mean it's..you know
这个结局太完美了
It's uh..it's perfect
就绪 -就绪
Set -set
开拍
And action
你想让我这么做的
You want this
如果你不想 就不会给我创造这样的条件
You wouldn't have brought me all this way if you didn't
还有谁会比Vince更合适导演最后一集呢
Who else would be the person to direct this last episode
有谁是比Vince Gilligan更合适的人选来将剧情推向结局呢
Who else should bring this story to a conclusion other than Vince Gilligan
更窃窃私语一些 更急促一些
Even more whisper,even quicker
把我送回家就好 剩下的我能做
Just get me home.I'll do the rest
他是整个剧的大脑 他是灵魂和核心所在
He is the mastermind,you know he's the soul of it,the heart of it.
我的意思是 你只能看见一个人影
I mean,all you see is a shape
但你可以看到这个人正往汽车后座走去
But you could see a guy going into the back seat
Vince应当得到最大的褒奖
Vince Gilligan deserves the lion's share of the preys
我是部剧的门面 但他和编剧们才是主心骨
I am the face of it,but he and his writing staff are the backbone
对我们来说 我认为这就是最好的告别方式
For us I think that's how we were able to say goodbye
就是知道
Is knowing that
最后一集中的每个选择都是由Vince定夺的
Every choice that was made ultimately came down to him,you know for that last episode
这让我们所有人都充满了十足的信心和激情
And I think that filled all of us with a lot of confidence and a lot of excitement
以及对于我们在做的工作 充满了自豪
And a lot of pride in what we are doing
她没那么可怜...她没那么可怜 -对
She's just not sorry enough…She's not sorry enough -right
你才是那个失去了一切的人 不是她 -对
And you are the one who's lost everything,not her -right
你才不在乎她住在一个又小又破的公寓呢 你失去了你的丈夫
You don't care she's living in a shabby little apartment,you lost your husband
这不仅仅是全剧的落幕
Not only was this the last episode of the series
但也正是因为 这是全剧的最后一集了
But because it was the last episode of the series
我们也将迎来许多角色的最后一次表演
We were seeing a lot of characters for the last time
我认为 演员生涯中会有些难以预料的事情
I think the life of an actor is very unexpected
谁会知道你的最后一场戏是你一个人独自演出
And in their last scene who knows you could find yourself alone in a scene by yourself
只有一个助理导演在你对面帮你读台词配戏
Having the assistant director read lines opposite you
而Betsy就是以这样一种方式谢幕的
And for Betsy's departure that was the case
你好 我现在不能接电话
Hello,I can't come to the phone right now
请在哔的一声后留言
Please leave a brief message after the sound of the beep
是我 我想要真相 行吗
It's me…Truth,all right
这场戏感情上相当复杂
That was a very complicated emotional scene
但她还要一个人独自完成
That she's doing on her own
我理解你 Betsy 真的
I understand,Betsy,I understand
-这太伤感了...
-it's sorry to see.... -
-是的是的 -看到这对姐妹.....
It is,it is -these two sisters...
她会为他们俩做任何事 两个人都是
Cuz' she would've done everything for either of them
拍摄这段时我的心都碎了
It broke my heart to shoot that
我跟Vince说
I told Vince that I said that…
Hank和Marie会为Walt和Skyler做任何事情
You know,hank and Marie would have done anything for Walt and Skyler
而且我也坚信这一点
And I believe that they would have done anything for them
然而Walt和Skyler却做了那些事情
And then for Walt and Skyler to do what they did
我说 只有一种可能Marie会原谅他们
And I said the only way I think Marie could forgive
那就是Hank起死回生
Is if hank came back
而那却是不可能的
And that's not happening
你待会打过去还是我来打
You want to call through later you want me to
-我会的 谢谢
-I'll talk to him,thanks
-不客气
-you got it
卡 太棒了 太棒了
Cut…Beautiful,beautiful,beautiful
检查摄像机胶片门
Checking the gate
非常好 非常好
Beautifuly done,beautifuly done…
Betsy这是大家送给你的
Betsy,we all wanted to give you this
-天哪
-oh,my god
Betsy干得不错
Nice job,Betsy…
我觉得 大家对你真挚的情感都凝结在我这句留言里了
And I think our heartfelt sentiment is echoed in what I wrote
我绝对会泡这个妹子
I would totally do her
完全表达了我的感情
It says it all
多谢大家
Thank you so much
谢谢你六年前给我这个机会 我说真的
I thank you for taking a chance on me six years ago,and I so mean it
这是我演员生涯 当然也是我人生中一段重要的经历
Like it's been such an experience of certainly my career but also my life
跟你们共事是一段美妙的时光
Just working with all of you it has just been so wonderful
我会想念你们的
I'm gonna miss you all
大家非常幸运能认识你 上帝保佑你
We're all so lucky to know you,we're so lucky to know you,god bless you
大家一起非常开心
It's been so much fun
你就不能给我个结结实实的拥抱吗
Will you give me a real hug
狠狠地抱一下 啊啊啊啊
Squeeze me hard ahhhhhhhhhhhh
只要你想 当然可以 这么多年了
I can do this,I can do this,if you want me,all these years
广受好评的电视剧《绝命毒师》在将进入最终季时传出了坏消息
Bad news for TV's most critically acclaimed series Breaking Bad as it heads into its final season
因Walter White这一角色而广受赞誉的主演Bryan Cranston
Actor Bryan Cranston renowned for his portray of Walter White on the show
刚刚经历了一起入侵盗窃事件
Has reported a breaking-in incident
有人从他的车内偷走了一集或甚至两集 机密的《绝命毒师》剧本
In which one and possibly even two top secret scripts have been stolen from his car
反正对宣传有好处 天哪 这太让人惊讶了
No such thing is bad for publicity,my god,it's amazing
你知道我的车被非法闯入了
You know my car was broken into
有人偷走了我的包 那里面有剧本
They snatched my bag with the scripts in it
现在好像就是炸开了锅
Now,it's like blown up
秘密是不是泄露了 最后究竟会发生什么
Is the secret going to be released  what's going to happen
这些采访...你们得看看这个 简直是....
The interviews,you've got to see this,it's just...
很大程度上闹得沸沸扬扬
It's been blown up to a large proportion
那不是最后一集的剧本
It was not the final episode,
所以还好 我们没泄密
So that's OK,we're safe from that
我们刚得到了揭露911事件真相的录像 敬请期待不要走开
We have the 911 tapes,stay tuned
令人震惊的最新发现
You're not going to believe,we just found out,you know
今天是RJ的最后一天 Walter Jr.的最后一天
So this is RJ mite's last day on the series,this is the last day for Walter junior
我们正在复合公寓群这里拍摄
And we're shooting here at an apartment complex
在最后一集 这里是非常重要的场景
That plays a very major part in the last episode
拍完最后的镜头 我们就要跟RJ说再见了 会很伤感的
It's gonna be sad we'll finally get the last shot and to say goodbye to RJ
你好吗 -天哪
How are you doing -oh my god
你身体能往前倾一点吗
Can you lean forward little bit
首播集里面Melissa Bernstein就坐在校车里
Melissa Bernstein was in the school bus in the pilot
而现在到了全剧的最后一集
And this being the last of the...the last episode of the series
Melissa要重新回到校车上 所以我们正在布置她坐的位置
Melisa is once again on the bus,so we're trying to position her
RJ上车的时候我们就能看见她了
So we can see her on the bus when RJ gets on
第三个垫子了 -是第四个 已经垫了四个垫子了
Third pad -I'm on the fourth…I'm on four pads
四个垫子 -现在到第五个了
Four pads -this is five
你们都看看 这太夸张了
Just so you know,this is ridiculous
Melissa Bernstein是个杰出的制片人
Melissa Bernstein was the most phenomenal producer
全体演职人员都是这样认为的
And across the board,the cast and crew feel that way
和她一起工作是件高兴的事
It's a pleasure working with her
她能做本剧的制片人我们非常幸运
And we're so lucky that she's the producer on the show
从一开始她就参与我们的工作了
She's been here from the beginning
她总有一天会主宰我们这个行业的
And she's going to run this town someday
她真的棒极了
I mean she is amazing
哪里开始就哪里结束 一个循环 从校车开始 -到校车结束
It ends where it began,full circle,school buses -school buses
开拍
Action
最后一集的剧情会让你像产生过敏反应一样难受 真的是那样
The last episode of Breaking Bad is an allergy,really
我们会看到Walt的行为带来的那些 苦楚的血腥的后果
We see all the sadness,all the carnage that Walter White's actions have brought
而这些后果 我认为最明显地体现在Walt Jr和Holly的身上
And we see that I think that most clearly in the persons of Walter Jr. And Holly
你能想象吗 失去了你的父亲 失去了你的家
Can you imagine losing your father,losing your house
你曾拥有的一切化为乌有
Losing everything that you've ever had
你整个人生都被毁掉了
Your whole life was destroyed
他们是这部剧里的无辜者
They are the innocence of the show
我觉得这两个孩子很好地概括了这部剧所有受害者的形象
I think all of the victims are probably pretty well summed up in the persons of these two children
好的 卡 非常好
Alright,cut,very nice -cutting
Mitte先生 请问你能过来一下吗 -什么
Mr. Mitte,come here,please -yes
你好吗 -我想说非常感谢 -谢谢你
How are you -I wanted to say thank you so much -thank you
谢谢你选择在我们剧组长大成人
For growing up on our set
成为那么优秀的年轻演员 做出那么出色的工作
And become such a fine young actor and doing such a great great work
上帝保佑你
God bless you man
六年来你的工作十分出色
You did wonderful job for six years now
我们想给你开个支票 -耶
We would like to hand you this check -yeah
哪家银行会给我兑啊
Who would accept it
你拿着这个随便到哪家银行都能拿到钱
You take that to any bank build up,cash up
我还没在这个上面留言呢 -你还没呢
I haven't sign this one yet -you haven't
我马上给你写 不过没有记号笔
It'll get signed,but I haven't got a sharpie
谁过来帮个忙 好了
-somebody get over here,there we are
我早就知道我们能保持良好状态
I knew we were gonna in good shape
在首播集服装店的那场戏里 Anna抛出来一句即兴台词
In the pilot when anna threw out an ad-lib in the clothing store scene
就是他在试牛仔裤的时候
When he's trying on the jeans,
你说 这裤子感觉很有轮滑风格
And you said yeah,just like a skater's wear
然后你就顺势接下来 我看起来像是个会溜冰的么
And you threw it back,do I look like a skater to you
我那时就想 这以后可该有意思了
I was like it's gonna be fun
致: 荧幕上最失败父亲的好儿子
To the best son of television's worst father
致: 荧幕上最失败父亲暨绝命债主的好儿子
To the best son of television's worst father you can never owe for
碉堡了
That is awesome
你是个棒极了的人 我爱你
You're a great great great person,I love you
我也爱你
I love you too
就绪 就绪 开拍
Set,set and action
Bryan和我拍了我们在一起的最后一场戏
Bryan and I did our last scene together and
绝妙的是我们能够以角色的身份来互相告别
It was so wonderful because in a way we got to say goodbye to each other as characters
我做的那些事
The things that I did
你得明白我为什么做了它们
You need to understand why I did them
天啊 你要是再敢说一遍你是为了这个家
Oh god,if you say one more time that you did this for the family…
我是为我自己
I did it for me
这就是这场六年情感波折的结束了
This is the end of a six-year,very emotional roller-coaster
用不着很费力 你就能想象这种心境
And…So it didn't take much to be able to conjure up
要知道 在这样一种很动情的环境下你很容易进入角色
You know in an emotional state that put you in the right frame of mind
我能看看她吗  求你了..
May I see her please…
卡 棒极了
And cut,awesome
后来在育婴室里 我们经历了一段小小的宁静时刻
And then we had that little peace in the nursery afterwards
那感觉太棒了
And it was amazing
因为小宝宝的原因 我们必须保持完全安静
Because we bad to be totally silent because of the baby
那是第一次 小宝宝必须真正睡着的场景
That's the first time the baby was actually sleeping
整个片场都被一种宁静温和的气氛笼罩了
It put this through a feel over the entire set of this calm,sort of placid
美好又安静 有点禅的意味在里头
Sort of beautiful,the zen thing
一度我和Bryan甚至提出来
You know,and Bryan and I actually said at one point
我们真该一直都这样做
We should do it like this all the time
-就绪 -就绪 -开拍
-set -set -action
那时我正看着我的女儿
As I'm looking at my daughter
全身都充满了情感
And I'm filled with emotion
我必须要跟她告别了
I have to now say goodbye
其实演那场戏时我本来准备不流眼泪的
And I actually meant to play that scene without tears
但是我感情上真的没有准备好
But I was just not emotionally prepared for that
因为周遭发生的一切对我的影响太大了
Because of the impact of everything that was going on
我们的摄影师Andy 在肩膀上扛着摄像机
Andy Voegeli,who is our camera operator,he's got this camera on his shoulder
他离我只有这么远了 因为他想近距离拍摄
And he is this far away from me,because you wanna get close
我看着我的女儿
And as I'm looking at my daughter
同时可以听到刚荣升为爸爸的Andy
I can hear Andy,who's a relatively new father
正在镜头后哭泣
He's crying behind the camera
并仍旧努力保持静止不动 稳住摄像机
And trying to be still holding the camera
那是很动情的一场戏
It was a very emotional scene
我透过目镜看的时候泪流不止
I got teared up looking through the eyepiece
你知道 我确信当时我发出来了一些抽泣的声音
You know,I'm sure there were some audible sighs and snuffs coming ahead of me
剧组人员也是一样悲伤
The crew as well
我们正在说再见 欢乐时光要结束了
We are saying goodbye,it was the end of run
很真诚的情感都自然流露了出来
And honest emotions were coming out
我熬过了剩下的一天 但是当Aaron出现时
I got through the rest of the day and then when Aaron showed up
我突然承受不了了
Then I was just,that was it for me
一下子感受到了分别的真实感
I was just,that just killed me
我突然意识到将要结束的这一现实
It was,I think then was the realization was hitting me that
短短数分钟内 寥寥几次拍摄以后
In a number of,in a matter of takes,in a matter of minutes
就真真正正结束了
It was really going to be over
卡
Cutting
检查摄像机胶片口
Check the gate
我们拍摄了Anna在《绝命毒师》的最后一场戏
We got the scene and that was anna's last shot on Breaking Bad
马上整个房间都充满了悲伤的情绪
And it became a very emotional room very quickly
当我们最后拍完Anna的那场戏以后
When we finish shooting that final scene with anna
我们的副导演将我们转移到舞台一角
Our assistant director moved us over to a different part of the stage
所以我们都可以聚在一起享受最后一刻
So that we could all gather together and enjoy that last moment
Anna最后那番再见和谢谢的演说非常感人 触动人心
And anna gave an incredibly heart-felt,touching goodbye and thank you
我感觉就好像..和艺术家们 和朋友们一起在进行着艺术创作
It's felt like,like I said,it's felt like making art with artists,with friends
我永远都会心怀感激的 非常感谢你们所有人
And I'm forever grateful and I thank you all so much
-我爱你们 我会想你们的 -我们也爱你
-I love you,I'll miss you -we love you too
Anna演的这个角色 像我说的 是个很难把握的角色
Anna playing that character and a tough role to hold as I say
而她演的却相当好
And she credited herself beautifully
她是一个非凡的演员
She is a marvelous actor
演的角色难度很高 还有点吃力不讨好
Playing a very hard,at times somewhat thankless part
我没法想象还有其他人能比她做得更好
And I can't picture anybody doing better
你好 Jack 你在家吗
Hello,jack,are you home
人家想跟你聊聊天 你现在有空吗
Jack,I want to talk to you for a second,you got a minute
-有兴趣买一架我做的发射器吗 -当然
-can I interest you in the launch tower -yeah
开拍
And action
天哪 看看你那乱蓬蓬的一头头发
Jesus,look at you with that head of hair
那是真的吗
Is that real
是的
Yes
不是一个假发  你来真的
That's not a wig seriously
你之前怎么光头呢 故意剃的吗
What were you doing before,shaving it
恩
Yes
上帝啊 那可是一头好发
Christ,that is one fine head of hair
我是说 没了它你看上去像坨屎
I mean,otherwise you look like shit,but...
也向你问好 Jack
Hello to you too,jack
希望一切准备就绪之后
Hopefully when it's all setting down
这会成为一个无比精彩 激动人心的 戏剧化的场景
It's gonna be a tremendously thrilling,exciting,dramatic scene
但是在这个纳粹俱乐部的布景里拍摄 我感觉在像地狱一样
But shooting inside this nazi clubhouse set was like hell
我讨厌它 每一分钟都讨厌
I hated it,just like the every minute of it
你能听到我吗
Do you hear me
停 很好
Cut,very nice
片场像是让你得了幽闭恐惧症一般压抑
It got very claustrophobic in the set
那里感觉非常紧张 非常昏暗 常常烟雾缭绕
It was very tight,it was very dark,it was often filled with smoke
你晚上擤鼻子的时候
You blow your nose at the end of the night
Rorschach Blot:罗夏墨迹测验
那鼻涕就像墨汁一样的
And it comes out looking like a Rorschach blot
你就会想 这种日子什么时候才是个头啊
You know,and you are a little like uh,when will this end
这是痛苦的折磨 我等不及它结束了
This is agony,I couldn't wait for it to be over
这一切得以顺利进行 还是因为那些伟大的演员
What made it do-able was because the great actors that we had
我们有Bryan 和Aaron
We had Bryan and Aaron
我们有纳粹一伙和Jack大叔
And we had the nazis,we had uncle jack
我们有Kenny和Todd
We had Kenny and we had Todd
他们是最可爱的纳粹组合了
Those are the most lovable bunch of nazis
任何人能与他们共事都很幸运
Anyone's ever had the privilege spending time with
我是开玩笑的 我是说这些演员
I'm joking,but I mean the actors
和他们一起共事非常愉快
Who play the roles were a pleasure to work with
他们让这个过程变得好受些了
And they made it easier
你知道我在说什么吗 你个狗娘养的
You see what I'm talking about,you son of a bitch
你看这像个搭档的样子么
This look like a partner to you
Walt有很好的理由去对Jesse发火 痛恨Jesse
Walt has in his mind,good reason to be furious at Jesse,to hate Jesse
但是最后一刻
But in that final moment
他还是没法扣动扳机杀了他
He can't pull the trigger on him
太棒了 太棒了
Oh,man -ah,wonderful wonderful
Aaron 你想尝试下别的方法吗
Aaron,anything else you'd like to try
我不是在给你下套子
Not a trick question
好吧 这个再试试看
Ah yeah let's try this one more
你拍戏的时候一直承受着这样的压力
You have that pressure behind you the whole time you are shooting
还有其他方法吗  有没有什么东西被我们遗漏了
Like is there anything else is there something we are missing
细节处理得怎么样 有什么细微的差别吗
What are the details any nuances anything
你想试试别的东西吗  有什么其他的想法吗
You wanna try something any idea
一直在进行着这种思考
You know,constantly doing them
然后 我就好像 不敢看着他
And then,I'm like can't look at him
他很害怕...
He's like scared and just...
那种愤怒呢 那种肌肉反应
What's it like ..the anger...the muscle memory
然后就...你甚至发起抖了
Then it's like...even it vibrates
行 我们开始吧 很棒
All right let's do it,excellent
我不会因为好像少了点什么就让他们再多拍一次
I'm not saying do one one more because I feel there's something lacking
因为这是我们最后一场戏了
Just because this is our last go-round
而且我希望他们能像我一样开心
And I wanted them to be as happy as I can be
我很高兴他多拍了一次
I'm so glad he took that extra take
因为即使之前那条拍的已经很不错了 他愿意再拍一遍
Because he took it,as deep as the previous take was
而且拍的更深刻了
He took it,and much deeper
开拍 卡
Action cut it
你知道 拍那最后一次枪战是个非常漫长而折磨人的几天
You know,the final shoot-out scene was a long grueling,torturous,a few days
二 一 砰
2.1.bang
但是真的超级有趣
But super fun,it really was
喊开拍后 你们就屏住呼吸
On action,you hold your breath
像这样 邦邦邦
It's gonna go bang bang bang..
拍这一场 绝对是超出一般的紧张程度的
Shooting this sequence was absolutely beyond intense
之后他也被推倒了
He's also slammed and into this thing
这个情况里头 你们随意发挥
And then,and then,in which you do whatever feels like
你们俩要做的就是抓紧不放
And all you duo doing is hang on
我们有个一连串的特技动作戏
We had a big stunt sequence
就是Jesse勒死Todd的戏
Where Jesse is choking Todd,taking him down
我们得确定特技动作什么时候加进来
And we had to figure out at what point the stunt tumbles are gonna come in
什么时候我们的演员回到他们的位置
And at what point the actors are gonna step back in
很好 很好
That's great,just great
我们有一个安全背心
We got a jerk vest
这是一件特技装备 是件背心
This is a stunt equipment it's a vest
我们还加上了一些锁链
And we tied some shackles to it
另外一名特技演员使劲拉
The other stunt man pull really really hard
我们让演员开始这段戏
We had actors start the sequence
勒人 把接下来的动作开个头
Do the wrap and start the action
停住不要动
Freeze
然后我们让大家静止不动 让我们的特技演员进场
And we stopped everybody,and we threw our stunt guys in there
让他们演主要的动作戏
Had them do all the major action
确保没人受伤
Make sure nobody got hurt
确保他们会撞上桌子 会狠狠地撞向地面
Make sure they hit the table and hit the ground really hard
停 别动
And freeze
然后我们让他们也停在那里
Then we had them freeze as well
再让演员们回来
Which like the actors get right back in
做无缝的衔接 然后我们...
And seamlessly,we are going to
后期做出来的效果会非常好
You know,the post's gonna be great
开拍
Action
与此同时还有Walt向Jack开枪的戏
And that all needs to be happening at the same time that Walt is shooting jack
类似于在爬行一样
Kind of crawling
他有点像 想坐起身够到烟
He kind of get up to this or something
这样我们可以在你身后拍这个重要的镜头
And in that way we put the camera behind you for the big thing
那样我们就可以不被约束在这个角落
In that way we are not jammed in this corner
那将会是个牛逼的镜头
And that would be a badass shot
我们还是要把这些每天的任务拍完
And again we still have to be making our days
每天都是很大很大的工作量
And these are very very long days
同一个镜头 把血准备好
Same shot,final blood
这类的角色并不难演
It's not that difficult to play these types of characters
甚至你在拍某条的时候
You know,you do it in a take
Bryan就在旁边开玩笑
And…You know…Bryan's running around joking
你懂的 跟Aaron打情骂俏
You know,joke with Aaron
你明白我是什么意思吗
You know what I mean
我们在互相捣蛋
We're busting each other's chops
这个角色对我没什么影响
And…It doesn't affect me
我又不会把什么黑暗心魔带回家 你知道的
I'm not bring home some dark demon,you know
你想要你的钱对吧
You want your money right
你想知道我把钱藏在哪儿
You wanna know where it is
你要是开枪就永远不知道...
You pull that trigger you'll never know…
检查
Checking
你们完工了 很棒 非常非常感谢你们
You're done,pretty nice,thank you very very much,excellent,thank you
拍Aaron的近景时
As Aaron is doing his thing in the foreground
我们可以把他的位置放在画面的左边
We could kind of put him in the left side of the frame
背对着我们 查看他的钥匙
Facing away from us,looking through his keys
或者在试他的钥匙
…Or trying his keys rather
同时Walt向我们走来
And Walt's coming our way
这样画面就平衡了 我们就这样做
And then so just tied over here,let's do that
好了 就是Aaron在近景
Alright,so it's gonna be a close on Aaron in foreground of the scene
Bryan出现在背景里
Bryan there in background…
我觉得这是最难拍的场景之一
That was I think one of the hardest scenes
因为我需要稳住 抑制住自己的情感
Because I was just,me trying to hold it together
我不能崩溃
Aaron,me trying to just not fall apart
还有就是Jesse终于能逃脱这一切了
Also because Jesse was…He's finally getting away
他再也不会见到这个人了
And he's never gonna see this guy again
开拍
And action -action
他非常恨他
And he hates him so much
但是他也很爱他
Um…But he did have a lot of love for him
他一直在寻找一个父亲般的人
You know,he was striving to find that fatherly figure
他在Mr White身上找到了那种感觉
And he found it in Mr. White
Aaron拍这场戏还是下了苦工的
Aaron did it a bit hard and
他意识到这将是
He was very aware that this was gonna be
他们的最后一面
The last moment where he's looking at Walt and they're looking at each other
最后的每一分钟都让他很是情绪激动
And every one of those last moments was very emotional to him
卡 很棒 很棒 谢谢你们
And cut,that was very nice,very nice -cutting -thank you
-Andy你觉得怎么样
-how that feel for you Andy
-这是最好几个了 -我也这么认为
-those are the best ones -I think so too
当Jesse开着车远离这疯狂的一切
You know when Jesse drives away from all this madness
我觉得他就想抓紧时间离开这里
I imagine him just getting the hell out of dodge
可能会去看Brock
Maybe going to see brock somehow
那真的是他会去道别的唯一一个人
That is literally the only person he will go to…To say goodbye
所以一旦他向Brock说了再见
So once he says as goodbye to brock
我猜他 可能会去阿拉斯加做个小木匠
I imagine him…You know,going to be a carpenter in Alaska
或者 在新西兰做个丛林飞行员 谁能说得准呢
Or…You know,maybe a bush pilot in New Zealand…Who knows
可以肯定的是 他是彻底离开毒品交易圈了
Just he's getting out of the drug business…That's for sure
他得努力 这需要很长一段时间
And…And he's just gonna try…That's gonna take him a long time
但是他会努力使这些伤口愈合
But he's gonna try to heal those wounds
我觉得他的未来会很美好
And I see a bright future for him
不会用太长时间的
It's not gonna be for a long time,you know
我们编剧为最后一刻想了很多种方案
The writers and I went through a lot of permutations for the very ending moment of the story
想了好几个月
And we went through them many months
好像一年多以前我们就开始谈论这些构思了
Probably we started talking about this a year or more
在我们着手开始写之前
In advance of actually conceiving it and writing it
你认为应该表现为受到启示吗 或者不是
Do you actually see it as inspired do you not
我们要借鉴《虎豹小霸王》那样的风格吗
Do we go out in a Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid kind of moment
虎豹小霸王：讲述两名劫富济贫的盗贼故事的西部片
是故意挑衅警察然后被射杀吗
Is it suicide-by-cop
是这样吗 是那样吗
Is it this  is it that
我们最后停在一个最基本的问题上
What we finally landed upon was the basic question of
Walt要的是什么
What is Walt want
在这个特定的时刻 他还想追求什么
Where is his head really at in this given moment
然后我们就对自己说:要不要来点深刻的东西
And we said to ourselves: Wouldn't it be a kind of poignant
就是那种独特的 只有《绝命毒师》才能Hold住的辛辣尖锐
That weird kind of only-breaking-bad-can-pull-it-off kinda way
他是那么热爱制毒的事业
That it's precious as it were
以致于他在他苟延残喘之际也想待在制毒室里
That he spent his last moment on earth with is his meth lab
那个他设计并运作的制毒室
His…Lab that he designed and brought fruition
《绝命毒师》的最后一个场景
The last scene of Breaking Bad
整部剧就要在这里结束了
…The entire…Entire series over here
就绪 -开拍
Set -and action
制毒室里的器械仿佛有不可思议的能量一般
The lab equipment became like a talisman
抚摸着这些东西让他回想起他教Jesse制毒的时光
Touching is remembering his tutelage of Jesse
这样的回忆就像兴奋剂一般
This moment gave him just enough adrenaline
多给了他几分钟的生命
To last to be alive for an extra couple of minutes
死前最后一次触摸
Put one final touch on your
触摸那些证明你存在过的东西 再离去
On your existence before you go
很漂亮 很棒 我们再拍一条吧
Beautiful,that was great -cutting -this is absolutely and let's do one more
Vince描述最后一个镜头的时候说
The last shot that has been described that he wanted
他想让Walt倒在制毒室的地板上并慢慢死去
Was Walt on the ground in the lab and he's dying
然后摄像机向上 向上 向上
And the camera is pulling up,pulling up,pulling up
我们正在想怎么才能做到
And we're trying to figure out how to do this
我们去问Michael 我们出色的摄像指导
We went to Michael Slovis,our wonderful cinematographer
我们说Michael 你有什么想法吗
And we said Michael,do you have any ideas
Michael说 知道吗 我们不应该在这里拍
And Michael said,you know what,we shouldn't do it here
我们得在舞台上拍
We should do it on stage
因为摄像机吊车在这里不能达到那个高度
Because we couldn't get high enough up with the crane
他们实际上在我们的摄影棚做了个和围场那边一模一样的布景
At the compound,they actually recreated the set here on one of our stages
因为天花板足够高 能够拍到Vince想要的镜头
Because the ceiling is high enough to get the shot that Vince wants
所以在我身后有个巨大的专业吊车
So we have an enormous technic crane behind me
但还是不够高
That still don't go high enough
所以我们把这个巨大的吊车放在了脚手架上面
So we put the giant technic crane on top of the giant scaffolding
达到需求的高度
To get high enough up
这就是Walt咽下最后一口气的地方
And this is going to be where Walt takes his final breath
你能把眼睛睁到多大 能再大一点吗
How wide you opened your eyes pretty much a little bit
我可以再睁大一点 -实际上我觉得...
You know I can open it up a little wider -I don't know...actually I
对 你现在这样就很好了
Yeah,actually what you are doing right now was pretty good
我想让他死时的神情有种模棱两可的感觉
I wanna maintain an ambiguity about his look
-他的眼睛是闭上的吗 -睁开的 -是吗
-will his eyes be closed -open -they'll be open
我们之前谈过这点
We talked about that too
我觉得我们需要这样做 眼睛得睁开
I just think we deserve it…We need to have it open
眼睛闭着的话 好像是说他释然了
When eyes are closed,there's more sense that he's at peace
我并不想传达非黑即白的意义
And I don't really want to convey one thing or the other
就绪-就绪 -开拍
Set -set -and action
我们不仅仅探讨Walt带来的外在的危险
We explored not only the physical danger what
包括他带给他自己的 他的家人还有他的朋友的
Walt has subjected to himself and his family and his friends too
还有情感上的危险
But the emotional danger
他作为一个自然人来说遭遇了什么
What has happened to him as a human being
灵魂的堕落
Degradation of his soul
自我的膨胀
The inclusion of ego and hubris
从未有过的坏的特质在他身上出现了
He developed an adverse nature which he never had before
于是将这些负面的情感特质融入了进来
So those kind of negative emotional traits played in
行动
Move…
我想最后一刻还有一丝胜利的意味
I think there's an element of victory to be hung here
它很微妙 但确实在那
It's subtle but it's there
结局恰如其时 又如他所愿
He ended things the moment he wanted to end them,on his own terms
我觉得 他对于自己的犯下的种种罪孽后悔不已
I think he has got a great many regrets on a great great many sins under his belt
那些让他愧疚的事 那些他希望从未发生的事
Things he was sorry for,things he wished he never done
但是那时已经没有后悔药可以吃 没有回头路可以走了
But there's no going back and doing them at that point
他能做的就是把这些恩怨给了结了
All this guy left to do is take care of his business
然后把剩下的钱给他的妻儿
And gave his remaining money to his children and his wife
最后 像个牛逼闪闪的大坏蛋一样死去
And then,gone like a god-damn man
而这就是他所做的
And that was what he does
好了 卡 非常棒
Alright,cut…Very good -cutting
APD：Albuquerque Police Department
非常感谢你们 Albuquerque警察局的同志们
Thank you very much to the APD
干得漂亮
Well done APD
大家的表现都很好哦
Good job everybody
谢谢你们 来击个爪 来
Thank you…Bong…Bong…
全剧最后摄制日:第五季第十四集 奥西曼提斯 引子
最后一天了
It's the last day
看看我们勇敢无畏的头头
Our fearless leader
我开始难过了
I'm starting to get very sad
这是《绝命毒师》拍摄的最后一天
This is the last day ever of Breaking Bad
可能一个小时后就能杀青了 可能还会更快
It's gonna be series wrapped probably within the next hour,if not sooner
我感觉到真的是要结束了 我开始有点...
And it's starting to hit me I'm starting to get ...
没有人为这部剧即将结束而开心
Nobody's happy about finishing the show
因为大家都那么在意彼此
Because we all care for each other so much
我们为我们的工作而自豪
And we are so proud of the work
我们热爱这些角色 我们热爱这个故事
And we love these characters,and we love the story
我们将在这个特定的地方结束拍摄
But the fact that we are doing it here
而且 我们拍摄的是首播集的闪回情节
And the fact that we are ending with this flashback moment where we get to leap back to the pilot
这两件事从我的创作角度 以及我的情感角度上来看
From my creative standpoint,and sort of a sentimental standpoint
都是非常美妙的
Is really wonderful
我在想或许这周末我们全家可以聚一聚
I was thinking that maybe we can have a little family time this weekend
这个场景直到今天才拍摄 是出于很实际的原因
There was a pragmatic reason for us to be here on this last day,where we started this
那就是我和Aaron的胡子
And that was,our beards
很显然 我肯定得把胡子剃了才能拍这一部分
So,obviously I couldn't have a beard to shoot this segment
我觉得太幸运了 能够执导这一集我感到很荣幸
I felt just beyond lucky,I felt privileged just be able to be doing this episode
因为Walt和Jesse看起来像在试播集里一样
Because Walt and Jesse look like they did in the pilot
我不知道怎么说 我觉得我真的很幸运
I don't know man,I feel pretty damn privileged
-先生们 他们准备好了
Gentlemen,they are ready for you
我才没有准备好
Oh,I'm not ready for them
我没准备好
I'm not ready
Aaron只是在用这些失落的碎碎念来开玩笑
Aaron was just mucking around with a mantra of depression
嗷..嗷..嗷.. 额 我天
Oh.no...oh..Jesus
比如这太可怕了 这太糟糕了 然后还露出这种表情
Like,this is horrible,this is awful and he looked like this
他很可爱 不至于说是天真无邪 但是从我们相遇 他就如此可爱
He was as sweet and,not quite as innocent but as sweet as the day we started
啊 好难过
Oh,this is terrible
我准备好退出了吗 我想可能是的
Am I ready to hang up these cleats I guess so
但是很明显我已经对Jesse Pinkman 这个角色产生了个人情感
But obviously I have a such personal relationship with Jesse Pinkman
我非常喜欢他
And I love him dearly
我很难过我再也不能演Jesse了
And it's sad to me that I will never play Jesse Pinkman again
哟 接下来要做什么
Yo,so what's next
等
We wait
我们不是应该还有八件屁事要去做吗
Don't we have like 8 more anal things to check
Aaron是个非常感性的人 是个情感外露的人
Aaron is somebody who is so emotional,absolutely heart on his sleeve
感知能力很迅速很深入
And who feels things very immediately and very deeply
我觉得Bryan作为他的依靠 能帮助Aaron过完这最后一天
And I think it's gonna help Aaron quite a bit to get through the day having Bryan as an anchor
卡 核对中... -爱死这段了
Cutting,checking -love it
我们转过去再拍
And we will turn around
觉得我这大师级的特写镜头咋样啊  哈哈 顺便说一句 我得走了
How's my master close-up  haha,by the way I have to go
剩下的能让Sean上来演吗
Can we get sean in here to do the thing
我真的想上路回家了
I'd really like to get on the road
避开交通拥挤什么的...那就太好了
You know,beat the traffic and everything  that'd be great
有谁反对吗
Anybody have an objection to that
没事啦 大家再见
OK,good,bye,y'all
谢了 你们俩能过来拍吗
-thanks very much -will you two turn around in here
最后一个镜头 Christine
Final shot  Christine
我是最后一个镜头  我就说嘛
I'm the last shot  that's what I'm talking about
啊啊啊  这真是噩梦啊
Ah,it's nightmare
Bryan定了基调 他会让你觉得 不用难过啊
Bryan set the tone,that,you know,it's gonna be OK
我们走了那么远 这件事应该是让我们感到开心和荣耀的
And you know it's a long road and this is something to be happy about and to honor
保持快乐的心情才是我们这段体验最重要的部分
But you know but to really keep the joy at the forefront of this experience
我觉得他的观点帮助了我们所有人
And I think his perspective helped us all
-没事的 -天呐 别看着我
It's OK -Jesus don't even look at me
我们马上要拍《绝命毒师》最后一个镜头了
We are about to shoot the very last shot of Breaking Bad
我戴着太阳镜是因为我在哭
I'm wearing sun glasses because I'm crying
Rian是这集的导演
Rian Johnson is the director of this episode
但是他请我为最后一个镜头喊卡
But he asked me to call cut for the very final shot
可以了
There is good
来 我们整好你的小内裤 弄一下就好了
Tighty-whity.here we go,just a little
我很感动
And I was very touched by that
我那时想说我很期待
I was about to say that I'm looking forward for doing that
但其实并不是 因为当我那样做的时候
I'm not,because when I do that
就意味着正式剧终了 一切都结束了
It means it's officially wrapped,it's officially done,put to bed
但是那很让人感动 我很期待那一刻 会很好的
But that was very sweet,I'm looking forward to doing it,it'll be nice
如果可能的话 我想再拍一次我们之前拍的那场戏
I'd like to reshoot that scene we did earlier,if possible
好了 图像出来了
Alright picture is up
好了 开拍
OK -set,action
如果我们有个冰箱
Well,if we had a freezer
凝结液就会冷却地更快
The condensed liquid would cool more quickly
因为这是个放热反应
Because,of course,this is an exothermic reaction
意思就是会散发出热量
Which means giving heat off
你不如打昏了我算了
Put me into a coma,why don't you
别在这里抽
Not in here
你说什么 你做了什么
What do you say,what's happening here
-天呐 -你还在拍呢 是吧 -对
-oh my god -you still rolling right -still rolling
美利坚人民可都盼着这个呢
It is what America wants
好了 我们要拍了
Alright,here we go
开拍
Action
-别在这里抽 -你把我当做傻瓜呢
Not in here -duh. Like I'm an idiot
对 你就是我的小傻瓜
Yeah. Like you're an idiot
卡
And cut
Vince是我作为制片人最引以为豪的发现
Vince is one of my proudest if not my proudest sort of discovery as a producer
我知道他拥有非凡独到的见解
And I knew that he had such a special singular voice
我非常为他自豪 难以用言语表达的自豪
I couldn't be more proud of,I can't tell you how proud I am of him
非常感谢你们 我们就像一个大家庭
Thank you all so much,we're all like a family
我们马上 好像就要拆散这个大家庭一样
Wow we're gonna like break a family here
我永远不会忘记 这么非凡的经历
And I'll never forget.this is brilliant
所以 谢谢你们每一个人 愿上帝保佑你们
So any of you,thank you so much...god bless you
我们深知自己是如此幸运
We do know how lucky we are,how fortunate we've had
能够参与到这个过程中 尤其是能和这个人一起
To be on this ride,especially with this man here
一个创造了这个独一无二的环境和风格
Who has created an environment,a style
还有独特叙事手法的人
A storytelling that is so unique
我们都知道这会引起什么样的反应
And it is getting that reaction as we all know
他把我们带到这里 不仅仅改变了我的个人生活 职业人生
He brought us all here,not only change my life personally,professionally
还有Aaron的 还有所有演员所有编剧的人生
And Aaron's and all of the actors' but all the writers' too
还有有幸执导这部剧的导演
And the directors' who've ever been very fortunate to come on the show
你们造就了这一切
You have done all of that
你们还争取到了在新墨西哥州的拍摄权
And more,you've given credence filming here in New Mexico
和你所见过的首屈一指的工作人员一起合作
With a crew that is second to none,as you have met
我的心里满是你们的爱与支持 还有你们的才华
My heart is full with all your love and support and talent
我们非常感谢你们 愿上帝保佑你们
And we thank you so much and god bless you all
哦 天呐 看这是什么
Oh my goodness look at that
我会很想念你们的
I'm gonna miss you guys so much
好难过啊
It's terrible,this is awful
真的 我不想承认
It really is,I mean,such denial
你们每天精神充沛地 热情洋溢地来做这份工作
You guys,every single day you come with such passion and excitement for this job
我们也是 所以我们非常感谢你们
As do all we,so we all appreciate it,thank you
Vince 天呐 谢谢你
Vince Gilligan,my god,thank you
谢谢你创造了这样一部 出色的疯狂的危险的伟大的电视剧
For creating such a brilliant,crazy,dangerous and great show
我怎么感谢你都不足为过
I cannot thank you enough
Bryan
我就是  我很爱你
I just,I love you man,you know
啊啊啊 喵了个咪 我爱你啊 你知道的
Ah god,damn it,I love you man,you know it
我们很幸运有你做我们剧的主角
We are so lucky to have this man be our no.1 on the show
让我们再鼓一次掌吧
You know,let's just have another round of applause
你真的让我成了一个更好的演员
You truly have made me become such a better actor
更好的人
And I truly believe,a better person
谢谢
So thank you
我记得在我们拍第一季的时候
I remember we were shooting in the first season
我们又在某个尘土飞扬的地方拍戏
And we were rolling around another dirt somewhere and
在吃午饭的路上你说
We were walking to lunch and you said
啊 这是不是太棒了
Ah,isn't this great
脸上都是汗水和尘土
Full sweat and sand
我记得我跟你说 我说我希望你是这么觉得的
And I remember telling you,I said man that's my hope for you
我希望你会永远记住 我们是时间上最幸运的人
That you always remember that,that we are the luckiest people in the world
我们真的明白
We truly know that,understand that
-我们会永远联系在一起 互助 友爱 我爱你 -我也爱你
We'll be forever tied,thankfully,lovingly,I love you -I love you too
我并不觉得这部剧是我独有的
I don't really feel ownership
与其说是所有者 我觉得我更像是股东 如果这说得通的话
I feel like a shareholder instead of an owner if that make sense
我们能达到如今的程度是经过了很多人的努力的
It went through so many hands to get here
幕前幕后的很多人都做出了贡献
So many people in front of the camera,behind the camera contributed
造就了这部剧
And made this what it is
拍大合照啦 房车那边
Photo guys,down by the RV
这种大家庭凝聚的感觉很好
It's just been a wonderful feeling of family,of cohesion
这些人聚集在一起 我都不知道这一切是怎么发生的
All these people come together,I don't remember how it happened exactly
好像是命中注定一样
It just seemed to happened
全片结束
The end